原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译     辰星晓Reginamoon  kathy567  海云生
翻译     nemonini  Effy17  暴走小罐头  子V
翻译     TracyOY  布塔  金晨的小书包
校对     金晨的小书包  布塔
时间轴   西·查  Ans  罗大  caroline  壬虚浪影
后期     渔夫
总监     布塔
把美国人叫醒
国家歌剧院
我们活在暮光之界
We live in a twilight world.
黄昏之时无故人
And there are no friends at dusk.
你暴露了  这次围攻是幌子  目的是杀你
You've been made. This siege is a blind for them to vanish you.
但我已经和他们联系上了
But I established contact.
带你走或杀了你  我只有两分钟  你快决定
Bring you in or kill you. I have two minutes. Make up your mind.
东西在哪里
Where's the package?
衣帽寄存处
Coat check.
别动
Stay.
拿他的
你在干什么
你是谁
黄昏之时无故人
No friends at dusk, huh?
有你就行
You'll do.
带他到集合点
Get him to the rally point.
换衣服  乌克兰人找的是平民
Swap clothes. The Ukrainians are expecting a passenger.
我从没见过这样的封装
I've never seen encapsulation like this.
我们不知道它有多古老  但这玩意是真东西
We don't know how old it is, but it's the real deal.
你知道怎么出去吗
Did you have an out?
可以从维修隧道到下水道
Service tunnel to the sewer.
拿上这个  带上他
Take this. Take him.
走他那条路  我已经不信任我们的原路线了
Take his exit. I don't trust ours anymore.
你能拆掉它吗
Can you defuse that?
它们是同步的  里面还有吗
It's centrally synchronized. Are there more?
为了掩盖踪迹
Covering their tracks.
-为此不惜杀了观众吗  -他们的命不值钱
- Taking out the audience? - They're just the cheap seats.
救人不是我们的任务
That's not our mission.
现在是我的任务了
Mine now.
走吧
Walk away.
你没必要杀了这些人
You don't have to kill these people.
-他不是我们的人  -谢谢他帮忙了
- That wasn't one of us. - I'll take the help.
快走  快走
Go, go, go.
不是我们要的人
受过训练的人能坚持十八小时
A man can be trained to hold out for about 18 hours,
所以7点后你的同伙就安全了
so your colleagues will be clear by 7:00.
他只坚持了不到十八分钟
He didn't last 18 minutes.
他没什么好隐瞒的
He didn't have anything to hide.
你们带走的是无名小卒
You were smuggling a nobody.
太冒险了
It's risky.
还是说你指望着这玩意
Or were you counting on this?
致命毒药
Death.
中情局标配
CIA issue.
等你的同伙安全了  就放过你自己吧
Spare yourself, once they clear.
快到7点了
Almost 7:00.
时间过得真快
It's running fast.
我们得往回调一小时
We have to put it back one hour.
抠出来
Get it out!
信  条
欢迎来到来生
Welcome to the afterlife.
你一直处于人工昏迷状态
You've been in a medically-induced coma
期间我们把你救出了乌克兰  治好了你的嘴
while we got you out of Ukraine and rebuilt your mouth.
自杀药丸是假的
The suicide pills are fake.
为什么
Why?
这是个测试
A test.
测试
A test?
他们拔掉了我的牙齿
They pulled my teeth out.
我的人安全撤离了吗
Did my team get clear?
没有
No.
可能是俄国雇佣兵干的
Private Russians, we think.
有人泄密了
Somebody talked.
你没有
Not you.
你宁愿死也不愿意供出你的同伴
You chose to die instead of giving up your colleagues.
我们都觉得自己会冲进火场救人
We all believe we'd run into the burning building.
但在切实感受到热浪前  我们无法保证
But until we feel that heat, we can never know.
但你做到了
You do.
我辞职
I resign.
你不为我们工作了  你已经死了
You don't work for us. You're dead.
你的职责超越了国家利益
Your duty transcends national interests.
此事关乎存亡
This is about survival.
谁的存亡
Whose?
全人类的
Everyone's.
有一场冷战  冷酷无情
There's a cold war, cold as ice.
只需知晓其本质就会输
To even know its true nature is to lose.
没人能知道全部
This is knowledge divided.
我只能告诉你一个手势  和一个词
All I have for you is a gesture in combination with a word.
"信条"
"Tenet."
小心使用
Use it carefully.
它能打开正确的门  也能打开错误的门
It'll open the right doors, but some of the wrong ones, too.
他们只告诉了你这些吗
That's all they've told you?
你通过的那个测试
That test you passed?
不是谁都能通过的
Not everybody does.
穿着反光衣  拿着笔记板  几乎可以通行无阻
With a high-vis vest and a clipboard, you can get almost anywhere.
只是几乎
Almost.
这是不为人知的信条
An obscure tenet.
不要闲聊
No small talk.
别说出任何可能揭露我们身份或任务的信息
Nothing that might reveal who we are or what we do.
我还以为我是来接受任务的
I thought I was here to find out what we do.
你来不是为了任务  而是学习
You're not here for "what," you're here for "how."
任务是你的事  与我无关
"What" is your department and not my business.
为了完成我的任务
Well, to do what I do...
我得了解我们面临的威胁
I need some idea of the threat we face.
根据我的理解  我们想要阻止第三次世界大战
As I understand it, we're trying to prevent World War III.
核毁灭吗
Nuclear holocaust?
不是
No.
比那更糟
Something worse.
瞄准  扣下扳机
Aim it and pull the trigger.
没子弹
It's empty.
瞄准
Aim it.
看看弹夹
Check the magazine.
怎么回事
How?
其中一颗子弹和我们的一样  顺时间运动
One of these bullets is like us, traveling forwards through time.
另一颗逆时间运动
The other one's going backwards.
你能分辨出来哪颗是哪颗吗
Can you tell which is which?
现在呢
How about now?
它被逆转了  它的熵是逆向的
It's inverted. Its entropy runs backwards.
所以在我们看来  它的运动轨迹是逆向的
So, to our eyes, its movement is reversed.
我们认为这是一种核裂变引发的逆向辐射
We think it's a type of inverse radiation triggered by nuclear fission.
这不是你们造出来的
You didn't make it?
不是  我们还不知道要如何造
No, we don't know how yet.
那这是哪来的
So, where'd it come from?
有人在未来制造它们
Someone's manufacturing them in the future.
然后逆时间回到了我们这里
They're streaming back at us.
试试看
Try it.
你得已经把它放下了才行
You have to have dropped it.
我还没碰到它  它怎么就动了
How can it move before I touch it?
从你的角度看  你是接住了它
From your point of view, you caught it.
但从子弹的角度看  你是放下了它
But from the bullet's point of view, you dropped it.
但应该是先有因后有果
But cause comes before effect.
不  这只是我们的时间观念
No, that's just the way we see time.
那还存在自由意志吗
Well, what about free will?
如果你不把手放在那里  子弹也不会动
That bullet wouldn't have moved if you hadn't put your hand there.
不管正放还是倒放  都是你让这件事发生的
Either way we run the tape, you made it happen.
别试图去理解
Don't try to understand it.
去感受
Feel it.
凭直觉
Instinct.
明白了
Got it.
为什么感觉这么奇怪
Why does it feel so strange?
因为你不是在射子弹
You're not shooting the bullet,
而是在接子弹
you're catching it.
我之前见过这种子弹
I've seen this type of ammunition before.
执行任务时吗
In the field?
我差点被击中了
I was almost hit.
那你真是格外幸运
Then you were exceedingly lucky.
被逆向子弹击中会造成重伤
An inverted bullet passing through your body would be devastating.
很惨的
Not pretty.
这些像是现代的子弹
These look like today's.
虽然它们是现代制造的
They may have been made today
但在多年后被逆转了
and inverted years from now.
你从哪弄到的
Where did you get them?
那面墙上的  我负责研究它
Came with the wall. I was assigned it,
我还研究这里其它很多材料
like all the material I'm studying here.
你做过金属分析吗
Do you have an analysis on the metals?
当然  怎么了
Sure. Why?
合金成分也许能告诉我子弹是在哪里制造的
The mixture of alloys can tell me where they might have been made.
听着
Look...
这看起来不算什么世界末日
I'm not seeing Armageddon here.
子弹看起来不算什么  但机器很好操控
The bullet may not seem like much, but it's a simple machine.
铅弹  黄铜弹壳  火药
Lead bullet, brass casing, gunpowder.
如果他们能逆转子弹
If they can invert that,
应该就能逆转一切事物
I see no reason they couldn't invert pretty much anything.
即便是核武器  也只能影响我们的未来
Even a nuclear weapon can only affect our future.
但逆向武器也许还能影响我们的过去
An inverted weapon might be able to affect our past as well.
明确目标后
Now that we know what to look for,
我们找到了越来越多的逆向材料
we're finding more and more inverted material.
复杂物件的残片
Remnants of complex objects.
你觉得这些是什么
What do you think we're seeing?
一场未来战争的碎片
The detritus of a coming war.
-喂  -我们活在暮光之界
- Yep? - We live in a twilight world.
黄昏之时无故人  他们说你死了
No friends at dusk. I was told you left the building.
即便是死人也需要盟友
Even the dead need allies.
有什么具体要求
Specifically?
我在孟买需要帮手  我要见桑杰·辛格
I need an assist in Mumbai. I need to get to Sanjay Singh.
辛格
Singh?
他从不离开他家  而他家是...
He never leaves his house. And his house is...
-他的地盘  -确实
- his house. - Yes, it is.
我正看着呢
I'm looking right at it.
我看看谁能去
I'll see who's on deck.
两小时后去孟买游艇俱乐部
Bombay Yacht Club in two hours.
听说你急需
It seems you need an introduction to
见一位孟买名人
a prominent Mumbai local on short notice.
我是尼尔
I'm Neil.
我要见桑杰·辛格
I need an audience with Sanjay Singh.
那不可能
That's not possible.
最多十分钟就行
Ten minutes tops.
时间不是问题
Time isn't the problem.
问题是能不能活着出来
It's getting out alive that's the problem.
你会不会抓小孩当人质  女人呢
Would you take a child hostage? A woman?
有必要的话
If I had to.
我不想搞出太大动静
I'm not looking to make much noise here.
您好
Yes?
伏特加汤力  还有健怡可乐
Vodka tonic. And a Diet Coke.
怎么了
What?
你出任务时从不喝酒
You never drink on the job.
你知道得真多
You're well-informed.
干我们这行就得这样
Well, pays to be in our profession.
我更喜欢苏打水
Well, I prefer soda water.
你才不喜欢
No, you don't.
你会跳伞吗
How's your parachuting?
接受基础训练时我扭伤了脚
I broke an ankle during basic training.
辛格的房子不够高  不能跳伞离开
Singh's house isn't tall enough to parachute off of.
可以蹦极跳
It's bungee-jumpable.
有"蹦极跳"这个词吗
I don't think "bungee-jumpable" is a word.
可能没这个词
It may not be a word,
但这可能是我们离开的唯一方法
but it may be our only way out of that place.
这么说来  也可以这样进去
Or into it, for that matter.
我知道你累了  我也很累
I know you're tired. I'm also very tired.
退后
Stay back.
我在乌克兰差点被一种
I was almost taken out by a very
不寻常的子弹击中
unusual type of ammunition in Ukraine.
我想知道那是谁提供的
I want to know who supplied it.
我叫桑杰
My name is Sanjay.
你是
And you are?
不能聊两句吗
No chitchat?
不会有人回应的
There's no one at the other end.
总之没人会来救你们的
No one who's gonna help you, anyway.
趁热吃啊
Don't let it get cold.
我怎么知道是谁提供的
Why should I know who supplied it?
合金成分是印度独有的
Combination of metals is unique to India.
如果产自印度  那就是你的
If it's from India, it's from you.
-不错的猜测  -是推理
- Fine assumption. - Deduction.
就算是推理吧
Deduction, then.
这位朋友
Look, my friend...
枪从来都不能促进有成效的谈判
guns are never conducive to a productive negotiation.
我不是被派来谈判的
I'm not the man they send to negotiate.
也不是被派来做交易的
Or the man they send to make deals.
但有话可以直接告诉我
But I am the man people talk to.
不行
I can't.
我不能告诉你
I can't tell you.
你是个军火商  朋友
You're an arms dealer, friend.
干掉你我可一点都不会良心不安
This may be the easiest trigger I've ever had to pull.
透露任何客户的信息
To say anything about a client
会违反他奉行的信条
would violate the tenets he lives by.
如果你这么在乎信条  那你可以告诉我
If tenets are important to you, then you can tell me.
一切
Everything.
除非你不再拿枪指着我丈夫的头
Not while you have a gun to my husband's head.
桑杰  请给我们的客人倒杯酒
Sanjay, make a drink for our guest, please.
干杯
Cheers.
我是普丽娅
Priya.
你才是老大
This is your operation?
在男人的世界里  找个男人撑场面自有其用处
A masculine front in a man's world has its uses.
你要找的军火商是安德烈·萨托尔
The dealer you're looking for is Andrei Sator.
那个俄罗斯寡头
The Russian oligarch.
-你认识他吗  -我听说过
- You know him? - Not personally.
他靠天然气成为亿万富翁
Made his billions in gas.
他搬到了伦敦  据说和莫斯科那边闹僵了
Moved to London. Said to be on the outs with Moscow.
不错
Very good.
但让他发家的其实不是天然气  而是钚
Except the gas he made his billions from was actually plutonium.
但这些都不能解释你是如何以及为什么
None of which explains how or why
卖给他逆向子弹
you sold him inverted munitions.
我把子弹卖给他时  还都是普通的子弹
When I sold him the rounds, they were perfectly ordinary.
那他是怎么把让子弹逆转
So how did he get them inverted?
我们认为他充当的是中间人
We believe he's functioning as some sort of a broker.
连接现在和未来
Between our time and the future.
他能和未来沟通吗
He can communicate with the future?
我们都能  不是吗
We all do, don't we?
电子邮件  信用卡  短信
E-mails, credit cards, texts.
任何记录在案的东西都能传递到未来
Anything that goes into the record speaks directly to the future.
问题是  未来能否回复
The question is, can the future speak back?
我应该去查清楚吗
And I'm supposed to find out?
要想接近萨托尔  就需要一个新主角
To get anywhere near Sator would take a fresh-faced protagonist.
而你就像雏菊一样新鲜
And you are fresh as a daisy.
接近他
Get close.
看看他收到了什么  怎么收到的
Find out what he's receiving and how.
可以让英国情报部门参与吗
Is it safe to involve British Intelligence?
我有个萨托尔碰不了的线人
I have a contact who's out of Sator's reach.
你一定有脱身的计划吧
You must've had a plan for getting out.
但不是我钟意的计划
Not one I love.
先生  有什么需要吗
May I help you, sir?
我和克罗斯比先生约了午餐
I'm Mr. Crosby's lunch.
你指的是迈克尔·克罗斯比爵士吧
I presume you mean Sir Michael Crosby's lunch.
差不多吧
Presume away.
请跟我来
If you'll follow me.
没等你来就开始吃了  希望你不介意
Started without you. Hope you don't mind.
我会赶上的
I'll catch up.
请给我一样的
Same for me, please.
我去叫服务员
I'll send the waiter.
不  直接点就行了
No, just pass on the order.
我猜你对一位俄罗斯公民有些兴趣
I gather you have an interest in a certain Russian national.
英俄双籍人士  所以我得小心为上
Anglo-Russian. So I have to watch my step.
的确  他是情报部门的线人
Indeed. He's tapped into the intelligence services.
我警告过他们  他的情报不可靠  但是
I've warned them he's feeding them rubbish, but...
他们似乎并不在乎
they don't seem to care.
跟我讲讲他
Tell me about him.
我想你对苏联时期的秘密城市很熟悉吧
I assume you're familiar with the Soviet-era secret cities.
封闭的城市  地图上没有标识
Closed cities, not shown on maps.
建在敏感产业周围
Built around sensitive industries.
其中大部分已经开放  并改名成为普通城镇
Most of them have been opened up and renamed as regular towns.
但萨托尔的家乡并没有
Not the one Sator grew up in.
斯达尔斯克12
Stalsk-12.
在70年代  它的人口大约有20万
In the '70s, it had a population of about 200,000.
据说被废弃了
Thought to be abandoned.
废弃
Abandoned?
出了某种事故
Some kind of accident.
后来就成了地下核试验基地
After which it was used for underground tests.
两周前  基辅歌剧院被围攻的同一天
Two weeks ago, same day as the Kiev opera siege,
我们在西伯利亚北部检测到了爆炸
we spotted a detonation in northern Siberia,
就在斯达尔斯克12的旧址
just where Stalsk-12 was.
萨托尔从地图上的这片空白中出现
Sator emerged from this blank spot on the map
怀着雄心壮志
with ambition...
还有足够的钱跻身英国权势集团
and enough money to buy his way into the British establishment.
通过他的妻子
Through his wife?
凯瑟琳·巴顿  弗雷德里克·巴顿爵士的大侄女
Katherine Barton. Oldest niece of Sir Frederick Barton.
她在希普利拍卖行工作  在拍卖会上认识了萨托尔
She works at Shipley's. Met Sator at an auction.
婚姻幸福吗
A happy marriage?
实际上分居了
Practically estranged.
我该怎么接近萨托尔
Well, how do I get to Sator?
当然得通过她
Well, through her, of course.
你可能过高估计了我的吸引力
You may have an inflated idea of my powers of seduction.
你没希望
Hardly.
我们有一张隐藏的王牌
We have an ace in the hole.
你把戈耶的画装在购物袋里
You're carrying a Goya in a Harrods bag.
这是一个名叫阿雷柏的西班牙人画的赝品
It's a fake by a Spaniard named Arepo.
是我们从伯尔尼的一个贪污犯那里
One of two we've confiscated from
没收的两幅中的一幅
an embezzler in Bern.
另一幅呢
What happened to the other one?
进了希普利拍卖行  由凯瑟琳·巴顿鉴定过
It turned up at Shipley's. Authenticated by Katherine Barton.
进行了拍卖
Put on auction.
你觉得是谁拍下了
And who do you think bought it?
她丈夫
Her husband?
她知道那是赝品吗
Does she know it's a forgery?
不好说
Oh, it's hard to say.
有传言说她和阿雷柏关系亲密
Rumor has it that she and Arepo were close.
无意冒犯
Look, no offense,
但在这个世界上  你若想自称是亿万富翁
but in this world, when someone is claiming to be a billionaire...
穿廉价西装可不行
Brooks Brothers won't cut it.
我也是想节约开支
I'm assuming I'm on a budget.
先拯救世界  再平衡收支
Save the world, then we'll balance the books.
需要我推荐一位裁缝吗
Can I recommend a tailor?
我自己找吧
I'll manage.
你们英国人可没有以貌取人的专属权
You British don't have a monopoly on snobbery, you know.
不算专属权吧
Well, not a monopoly.
更像是控股权
More of a controlling interest.
能帮我打包吗
Could you box that up for me?
当然不能
Certainly not.
再见  迈克尔爵士
Goodbye, Sir Michael.
西北三区加农街
有什么需要吗  先生
How can I help, sir?
抱歉  我没有接到任何预约通知  你是...
Sorry, I wasn't notified of any appointments, Mr...
戈耶
Goya.
戈耶先生
Mr. Goya.
不  我听说你是鉴定戈耶的最佳人选
No. I'm told you're the person to see about Goya.
这太美妙了
That's extraordinary.
它值多少钱
What's it worth?
先别急
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
在估价之前  要进行很多鉴定
Lots of work to do before any kind of valuation.
溯源  显微镜检查  X光检查
Provenance, microscopic examination, X-rays.
但你的直觉呢
But what does your heart tell you?
您刚才说这幅画从哪里入手的
Sir, where did you say you acquired this drawing?
托马斯·阿雷柏
Tomas Arepo.
我从一个愤怒的瑞士银行家那里
I bought my Goya for cents on a dollar
低价买下了这幅戈耶的画
from an irate Swiss banker.
我追溯到阿雷柏  然后他告诉我是谁付了大价钱
Traced it back to Arepo, then realized I scored a bargain
拍了他的另一幅画
when he told me who paid top dollar
我才发现我捡了个便宜
for another one of his pictures.
-是你丈夫  -你捡了什么便宜
- Your husband. - Where's your bargain?
你的画显然是赝品
Your drawing's an obvious fake.
我的画是一副逼真的赝品
My drawing's a very good fake.
你比任何人都清楚
You know that better than anyone.
这个信息就是我捡的便宜
The information's the bargain.
我帮助别人欺骗我自己丈夫的信息
The information that I helped defraud my own husband?
我和你丈夫算是同行
He and I are in related businesses,
但是想和他结交很难
but he's a very hard man to meet.
如果你我能达成交易...
If you and I were to make an arrangement...
交易
Arrangement?
你这是勒索
You mean blackmail.
别怕用这个词
Don't be afraid of the word.
我丈夫就不怕
My husband isn't.
很遗憾告诉你  他已经知道了
I'm sorry to tell you he got there first.
他知道吗  他什么反应也没有吗
He knows? And he's never done anything about it?
为什么要有反应
Why would he?
他花了九百万美元
He paid $9 million for it.
跟他逼我们陪他度假的花费差不多
Barely cover the cost of the holiday he just forced us on.
你们去哪度假  火星吗
Where'd you go, Mars?
越南  坐我们的游艇  他的游艇
Vietnam, on our yacht. His yacht.
你准备了西装  鞋子  手表
You've got the suit. The shoes, the watch.
但我看你还是有点力不从心
Think you're a little out of your depth.
像你丈夫那样敛财的人
People who've amassed fortunes, like your husband's,
通常都不会容忍别人骗他的钱
generally aren't okay with being cheated out of any of it.
那幅画是他控制我的把柄
The drawing is his hold over me.
他用报警和坐牢那一套来威胁我
He threatened me with police. Prison. The works.
他控制着我
He controls me.
控制我见儿子  所有一切
My contact with my son. Everything.
想离开他本就不易  而现在已不可能
Leaving would never have been easy but now it's impossible.
不能反抗
You can't fight.
只能哀求
Just beg.
在越南  我试着再次去爱他
In Vietnam, I tried to love him again.
我想如果还有爱  他可能会把儿子还给我
Thought if there was love there, he might give me my son back.
我们坐在那艘破船上看日落
We sat on that bloody boat watching the sunsets,
重温我们过去的生活
imitating some earlier time in our lives.
他看起来很高兴  所以我问他了
He seemed happy, so I asked him.
他给我提了一个条件
And he made me an offer.
如果我同意再也不见儿子  他就会放过我
He'd let me go if I agreed never to see my son again.
我发泄情绪  带麦克斯上岸了
I expressed myself. I took Max ashore.
他打电话给我们道歉
He called us, contrite.
我们回去时
And when we got back,
我瞥见一个女人从那艘船上一跃而下
I glimpsed some other woman diving off the boat,
他则不见踪影
and he'd vanished.
我从没如此嫉妒过
I never felt such envy.
你看起来不像是会妒忌的人
You don't seem the jealous type.
我妒忌她的自由
Of her freedom.
你知道我多么渴望从那艘船上一跃而下吗
You know how I dream of just diving off that boat?
但你们还有一个儿子
But you share a son.
这就是我的现实
That's my life now.
你当时知道那幅画是赝品吗
Did you know the drawing was a fake?
不知道
No.
我和托马斯关系亲密  也许太亲密了
Tomas and I became close, maybe too close.
我失误了
I failed.
安德烈不相信失误  他只懂得背叛
Andrei can't conceive of failure, only betrayal.
但我没有背叛我丈夫
But I didn't betray my husband.
回想起来  也许我错失了良机
Retrospect, maybe I missed my chance.
然后他放阿雷柏走了
And he let Arepo walk free.
如果你真如你所说见过阿雷柏
If you'd actually met Arepo as you claimed,
你就会知道他已经不能走路了
you'd understand he no longer walks anywhere.
我们打电话谈的
We spoke on the phone.
他也没法打电话
He can't do that either.
-画在哪里  -怎么了
- Where's the drawing? - Why?
介绍我认识你丈夫
Get me an introduction.
我就让画消失
I'll take the drawing out of the equation.
没有画  就没法起诉  你就没有把柄了
No picture, no prosecution, no more hold over you.
我可能就是你的第二次机会
I might just be your second chance.
不  我不需要拯救
No, I don't need redemption.
我是指背叛的机会
At betrayal.
你丈夫的朋友吗
Friends of your husband's?
你知道会这样
You knew this was going to happen?
别担心  他们不会杀了你的
Don't worry, they won't kill you.
安德烈不喜欢
Andrei dislikes tangling
为这种事和当地执法机关纠缠
with local law enforcement on that level.
你肯定是特别不喜欢我的装束
You must've really not liked the look of me.
你的装束没问题
The look of you's fine.
最好赶紧把丑事做完
It's best to get to the nasty part
免得我之后不忍心
before I care one way or the other.
外套左边口袋里有个号码
There's a number in your left coat pocket.
别从家里打
Don't call from home.
你不会接我的电话了
You won't be taking my call.
别小看我
I might surprise you.
我一小时前就点辣酱
I ordered my hot sauce an hour ago.
我们能走了吗
Can we get going?
拜托
Please?
他要你亲眼看看
He wants you to see.
他总能得偿所愿
And he gets what he wants.
显然不是每次都是
Not always, apparently.
安娜说我们要去庞贝  去看熔岩
Anna says we're going to Pompeii and see lava.
对  我们一起去
We will. We'll go together.
我也会去
I'll be there, too!
我说了别小看我
Told you I'd surprise you.
他真可爱
He's a cute kid.
他是我的一切
He's everything.
画在哪里
Where's the drawing?
奥斯陆  在机场
Oslo. At the airport.
机场
The airport?
你知道自由港是什么吗
Do you know what a Freeport is?
是用来储存购得的艺术品...
A storage facility for art that was acquired...
但这些艺术品还未缴税
But not yet taxed.
我们构建了一个网络
We started a network.
建筑公司罗塔斯造这些设施
Rotas, this construction company, built them.
我介绍客户
I brought in the clients.
这些设施是避税天堂
The facilities are tax havens.
自由港
客户无需报关就能欣赏自己的投资
The clients can view their investments without importing them,
这样就可以避税
so they avoid paying tax.
就像是艺术品中转站
It's sorta like a transit lounge for art?
艺术品  古董
Art, antiquities.
-任何值钱的东西  -任何东西
- Anything of value, really. - Anything?
只要合法就行
Anything legal.
但它和瑞士银行系统不无相似之处
But it's not unlike the Swiss banking system.
不透明
Opaque.
您肯定也明白  大部分自由港其实就是仓库
As I'm sure you are aware, most Freeports are just warehouses.
但我们保证您在这里可以真正享有...
But here we ensure that you can actually enjoy...
罗塔斯在奥斯陆自由港有些资产  我猜画在那里
Rotas has assets in the Oslo Freeport. I'm guessing it's there.
保险库在这边
And this way to the vaults!
你猜
Guessing?
她猜
我们一年去那里四五次
We make trips there four, five times a year.
-去看艺术品吗  -还有其他勾当
- To view art? - And whatever it is he does.
其实安德烈根本不在乎艺术
Turns out art's of no importance to Andrei.
但他在乎自由港
But the Freeports are.
保险库的结构是基于五角大楼设计的
The structure of the vaults is based on the Pentagon.
每个保险库都是独立的
Each vault a separate structure within the others.
一个保险库受损不会影响到其它保险库
Damage to one structure won't compromise the others.
有些客户选择生物验证  可以从停机坪
Some of our clients opt for biometric access, straight in...
直接进来
off the tarmac.
从航站楼吗
From the terminal?
从他们的私人飞机
From their private planes.
当然了
Of course.
我们的物流部门在全世界
Our logistics department ships to and from
各个自由港之间运送货物
any other Freeport in the world
奥斯陆  塔林
无需经过海关检查
without customs inspection.
塔林  奥斯陆
你想去那里找什么
What are you hoping to find in there?
你真想知道
You really wanna know?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
带上衬铅手套
Bring some lead-lined gloves.
天啊
Jesus.
是核武器
It's nuclear.
你参观的时候
When you're on the tour,
留意防火设施
pay attention to the fire precautions.
文件特别怕...
Documents are vulnerable to...
火灾吗  当然了
Fire? Absolutely!
不  我是想说怕被喷水器淋湿
No, I was going to say water damage from the sprinkler systems.
我们不用喷水器
We don't use sprinklers.
这个设施几秒内就能用
The facility is flooded with halide gas,
卤素气体置换掉所有空气
displacing all the air within seconds.
你能演示一下吗
Can you show me?
我们会窒息的
If I did, we'd suffocate.
那员工怎么办
What about the staff?
卤素气体只会灌入保险库
Halide only fills the vaults,
员工只要随便进一个走廊就行
they just have to get into either corridor,
并且警报会在释放气体前十秒响起
and there is a 10-second warning.
至少还给他们留了十秒
At least you give them 10 seconds.
先生  客户选择我们正是因为对我们而言
Well, sir, our clients use us because we have no priorities
客户的财产高于一切
above their property.
天啊
Blimey.
所有门都是防火的
All doors are fireproof.
液压闭门器  简单的钥匙和电子触发装置
Hydraulic closers, simple key and electronic triggers.
一旦设施封锁  就特别容易打开
Surprisingly easy once there's a lockdown.
为什么要封锁
Why a lockdown?
电力系统会跳至自动保险状态  封闭外部的门
Power switches to fail-safes, sealing the outer doors,
但内部的门会恢复成出厂设置
but inner doors revert to factory settings.
就可以把锁撬开
And pickable locks.
轻而易举  真的
It's child's play, really.
轻而易举
Child's play?
他们在机场安保系统之内
They're inside airport security.
他们要操心控制温度和湿度  而非武装抢劫
They have to worry about climate control, not armed raids.
我们要怎么用足够的火力突破外围警戒
So, how do we get enough firepower through the perimeter
以触发封锁程序
to trigger the lockdown procedure?
自由港的后墙
Back wall of the Freeport.
你有主意了
You've got something?
你不会喜欢的
Not gonna like it.
你想用飞机撞上去
You wanna crash a plane?
不是从空中坠毁  别那么夸张
Well, not from the air. Don't be so dramatic.
我想让一架飞机冲出跑道
I want to run a jet off the taxiway
撞毁后墙  引发火灾
and breach the rear wall and start a fire.
要多大的飞机
Well, how big a plane?
这部分是有点夸张
Well, that part is a little dramatic.
他是马希尔
This is Mahir.
他的团队会搞定飞机
His team'll work the plane.
飞机上不能有乘客
There can't be passengers.
挪威货运
Norsk Freight.
他们用的是自由港西边的机库
They use the hangar on the west side of the Freeport.
你想撞毁一架货机  机组成员怎么办
You want to crash a transport plane? What about the crew?
我们会放下滑梯  把他们赶下去
We pop the slides, chuck 'em off.
在滑行中吗
On the move?
有什么问题  他们不会有事的
What's the problem? They'll be fine.
这似乎有点冒险
Well, it seems bold.
冒险还行  我以为你会说这是疯了
Bold I'm fine with. I thought you were gonna say nuts.
要是你们被抓住呢
And if you get caught?
不会的
We won't.
假如呢
And if you do?
大家会以为是恐怖袭击  但没人死亡
Everyone assumes terrorism, but no one's died,
所以快速引渡一下  就人间蒸发了
so swift extradition then lost in the system.
新闻都不一定会提及
It'll barely make the news.
这要看爆炸的规模
Oh, depends on the size of your explosion.
实际上  金条可能也要出镜一下
Well, actually, the gold bars might get some play.
金条
Gold bars?
挪威货运每个月都会给财政部运一次金条
Norsk Freight ships Treasury gold once a month.
把机尾炸了  把金条倒在跑道上
Blow the back. Drop it out on the runway.
没人会注意到自由港  我保证
No one will be looking at the building. I guarantee you.
五角设施中心的空间太大了
The space in the center of the pentagon is too big.
那里肯定有什么
There's something there.
猜不出  根本没有标记
Can't figure it out, it's just not marked.
憋了45秒
That's 45 seconds.
足够了
Ample.
要是跑起来呢
Won't you be running?
好了  轮到你了
All right, it's your turn.
开始装箱
Start packing.
先生们  请过安检门
Gentlemen, if you would, through the detector, please.
给您
Sir?
还有您
And, sir.
要来杯咖啡或者水吗
I can offer you, perhaps, a coffee, water?
我来杯浓缩咖啡
No, I'll take an espresso.
-您呢  -不用了  谢谢
- Sir? - No, thank you.
好的
Excellent.
这飞机上的人都吃素吗
Is everybody on this plane vegetarian?
因为这里全是素食
Because all I got here is vegetarian.
这个看着像肉
So that looks like meat,
但那个像是素食
but I think that looks vegetarian.
我觉得都像是素食
I think they both look vegetarian.
不知道  真奇怪
I don't really know. It's confusing, ya know?
好了
Okay.
这边  先生们
This way, gentlemen.
先生们  你们的储藏室
Gentlemen, your assigned compartment.
继续开  别碰无线电
Carry on. Not the radio.
出来
Let's go.
瑜伽
Yoga.
下去  快点
Let's go! Now!
快快快
Go, go, go!
好吧
Right.
你说过有十秒  对吧
You said 10 seconds, right?
这里还有其他人
There's someone in here with us.
-需要帮忙吗  -确实需要
- Need a hand? - Actually, yes.
别碰
Don't touch them!
这里到底发生了什么
The hell happened here?
还没发生
It hasn't happened yet.
别杀他
Don't kill him!
得搞清楚我们有没有暴露
We need to know if we've been compromised.
你为什么来这里
Why are you here?
你是谁
Who are you?
你怎么知道我们会来
How'd you know we'd be here?
我们得走了
We need to go.
另一个家伙呢
What happened to the other guy?
搞定了
Took care of him.
我知道的太多了
Well, I've seen too much.
我还活着  这意味着你决定相信我
I'm still alive, which must mean you've decided to trust me.
也许我已锐气不再
Or maybe I lost my edge.
你还是宝刀未老
Edge is still intact.
有一场冷战
There's a cold war.
核战争吗
Nuclear?
时间之战
Temporal.
时间旅行吗
Time travel?
不
No.
有一种技术可以逆转物体的熵
Technology that can invert an object's entropy.
你是说逆转时间顺序
You mean reverse chronology.
就是费曼和惠勒的观点  正电子是在时间中
Like Feynman and Wheeler's notion that a positron is an electron
逆行的电子
moving backwards in time?
没错  我就是这个意思
Sure, that's exactly what I meant.
我有物理学硕士学位
I have a master's in physics.
好  那你得跟上进度
Well, try and keep up.
你的言下之意是...
The implications of this are...
绝密
Beyond secret.
那你为什么让我加入
Then why'd you bring me in?
我以为我们会找到一幅画和几盒子弹
I thought we'd find a drawing and a couple boxes of bullets.
我比你更意外
Not as surprised as I was.
我要回孟买寻找答案
I'm going back to Mumbai to get some answers.
我会安排你做中间人  但别忘了  对你来说
I'll set you up as a go-between. But remember, to you...
钚才是最重要的
it's all about plutonium.
我们完事之后  他们会杀了你
And when we're done, they'll kill you.
无论如何你都要去吗
Won't you have to do that anyway?
我也希望我有得选
I'd rather it be my decision.
我也是
So would I.
也许吧
I think.
这是你干的吗
Your work?
奥斯陆黄金运输机撞毁
是恐怖袭击  抢劫  还是两者兼具
你在保险库里发现了什么
What did you find in the vaults?
两个对手  一个是逆时间的
Two antagonists. One inverted.
我们解决了正时间的那个  逆时间的那个跑了
We took out the regular one, but the inverted one got away.
两个是同时出现的吗
Both emerged at the same moment?
对
Yeah.
他们是同一个人
They were the same person.
萨托尔在那个保险库里建了个旋转门
Sator's built a turnstile in that vault.
旋转门
Turnstile?
逆转时序的机器
A machine for inverting.
你说过那种技术还没发明出来
You've told me that technology hasn't been invented yet.
是没有
It hasn't.
是未来的人给他的
He's been given it by the future.
为什么
For what?
你最有可能找到答案
You have the best chance of finding out.
-你见过他吗  -差点就见到了
- Have you met him? - I was close.
要是你有他需要的东西呢
What if you have something he needs?
比如呢
Such as?
钚241
Plutonium-241.
在基辅歌剧院围攻中  萨托尔想从中情局手里
Sator tried to lift the only loose 241 from under a CIA team
夺取唯一流落在外的钚241
at the opera siege in Kiev.
他搞定了中情局小队
He got the team.
却没拿到钚241
Not the 241.
谁拿到了
Who did?
乌克兰安全局
Ukrainian Security Services.
一周后要转移到塔林
It's moving to Tallinn in a week.
我不能帮军火商
Helping an arms dealer
盗取武器级别的钚  普丽娅
steal weapons-grade plutonium is unacceptable, Priya.
我要干掉他
I'm just gonna take him out.
不不不  萨托尔必须活着
No, no, no. Sator has to stay alive.
他必须活着  直到搞清楚他扮演何种角色
He has to stay alive until we know his part in things.
利用这个形势
Leverage the situation,
同时不能失去钚241
without losing control of the 241.
这太危险了
It's too dangerous.
恐怖分子的炸弹就算能杀死数十亿人
A terrorist's bomb, even one that can kill billions,
如果我们不阻止萨托尔
is nothing compared with what will happen
造成的后果远比那严重
if we don't stop Sator.
什么后果
From doing what?
我们正遭受来自未来的袭击
We are being attacked by the future.
萨托尔在帮他们  你得查出他是怎么做到的
And Sator's helping. You have to find out how.
我看到了奥斯陆的新闻  你拿到画了吗
I saw the news from Oslo. Do you have the drawing?
你不用再担心画的事了
You don't have to worry about it anymore.
你把它毁了吗
You destroyed it?
我觉得你应该不想要了
I didn't think you'd want it back.
他知道吗
Does he know?
还不知道  静观其变吧
Not yet. So sit tight.
静观其变
Sit tight?
我儿子和那个魔鬼相处得越多
Every day my son spends with that monster,
他就越讨厌我
he thinks a little less of me.
不会太久的
It won't be long.
与此同时  把我介绍给他
In the meantime, introduce me.
以什么身份
As what?
我曾任美国驻利亚德大使馆的一等秘书
I'm a former first secretary from the American Embassy in Riyadh.
我们去年6月在派对上认识的
We met at a party last June.
我们在利亚德参加过派对  但好像不是6月
We were at a party in Riyadh, but I don't think it was in June.
是6月29日  7点或7点半
It was June 29th. 7:00 or 7:30.
菜单上是三文鱼
Salmon was on the printed menu.
但那晚换成了鲈鱼
Swapped for sea bass on the night.
萨托尔提前走了  然后你遇见了我
Sator left early. That's when we met.
我在伦敦希普利拍卖行碰到了你
I came into Shipley's in London.
你又在这里碰到了我
You ran into me here
你想带我看你的游艇
and wanna show me your yacht.
他会觉得我们俩有私情
He'll think we're having an affair.
然后他就会想见我
Then he'll wanna meet me.
或者杀了你
Or have you killed.
这就不用你担心了
Let me worry about that.
我看着像担心吗
Did I look worried?
包括船员能乘载七十人
Sleeps 70 with crew.
有两架直升机  导弹防御系统
Two helicopters. Missile defenses.
防海盗吗
Afraid of pirates?
安德烈的生计就是挑拨各国政府间的关系
Andrei lives playing one government off the other.
一旦他们翻脸  这就是他的避难所
The day they turn, that's his refuge.
我能跟你上船吗
May I join you?
沃尔科夫现在大概不载客
Not sure Volkov's taking passengers just now.
那就搭我的船吧
Then we'll take mine.
麦克斯
Max!
那个美国人是谁
Who's the American?
一个朋友
He's a friend.
希普利拍卖行的那个
The man from Shipley's.
你想狠揍一顿的那个
Who you tried to have beaten up.
我再问一遍  他是谁
I ask again, who is he?
我们去年6月在美国驻利亚德大使馆认识的
We met in Riyadh last June at the American Embassy.
作为外交官  拳脚有些太厉害了
Good with fists for a diplomat.
安德烈  你就喜欢疑神疑鬼
Paranoia's your department, Andrei.
他看着人不错  我请他来吃晚餐
He seems nice. I invited him to the dinner.
麦克斯
Max?
他去参观庞贝和赫库兰尼姆古城了
He's visiting Pompeii and Herculaneum.
你把他送走了
You just sent him off?
我答应跟他一起去的
I promised him I'd go with him.
我跟他说了你正忙着
I explained you were busy.
见朋友
With your friend.
别乱摸  哥们
Hey, easy, fella.
在我的家乡  你得先请我吃饭才行
Where I'm from, you buy me dinner first.
-萨托尔先生  -别废话了
- Mr. Sator. - Don't bother.
告诉我  你跟我老婆上过床了吗
Just tell me if you've slept with my wife yet.
没有
Uh... No.
还没有
Not yet.
你想怎么死
How would you like to die?
老死
Old.
那你选错职业了
You chose the wrong profession.
前面有个带围墙的花园
There's a walled garden up the road.
我们要把你带过去  割断喉咙
We are going to take you there, cut your throat.
不是横着割  而是在中间开个洞
Not across. In the middle, like a hole.
然后把你的蛋切下来塞在洞里
Then we take your balls and we stuff them in the cut,
堵住气管
block the windpipe.
真复杂
Complex.
看着讨厌的人在窒息而死前
It's very gratifying to watch a man you don't like
挣扎着想把自己的蛋从喉咙里扯出来  很令人满足
try to pull his own balls out of his throat before he chokes.
这就是你的待客之道吗
Is this how you treat all your guests?
我们说完了
We're finished.
你喜欢歌剧吗
Do you like opera?
你想说什么
Well?
不能在这说
Not here.
你会驾驶帆船吗
You sail?
我上船玩过
I've messed around on boats.
明早8点来码头  不只是玩玩
Be on the dock at 8:00 ready to do more than mess around.
明早8点
8:00 a.m.
麦克斯今年缺太多课了
Max has missed too much school this year.
我要带他回英国
I'm taking him back to England.
学校不会允许他这个学期缺这么多课的
The school won't be okay with him missing so much of the term.
-他们会允许的  -能听我说完吗
- Yes, they will. - Can I finish?
你表面上看起来尊贵
You have all the trappings of a king.
但我们都知道你是个玩弄权术的卑鄙小人
We both know you're a grubby little man playing power games
控制着不再爱你的妻子
with a wife who doesn't love you anymore.
你今天似乎
You seem...
很有精神
spirited today.
-是吗  -是的
- Do I? - Yes, you do.
你担心画被毁了吗
Were you worried it had been destroyed?
放心吧  我的直觉告诉我  把它从保险库取出来
Rest assured, instinct told me to remove it from the vault.
我对未来的直觉一向很准
I've always had instincts about the future.
所以我才能创造出这种生活  虽然你不再珍惜
That's how I built this life you no longer value.
驾船还是潜水
Sailing or diving?
出水
Rising!
歌剧院的事你知道多少
What do you know about opera?
2008年  一个偏远的俄罗斯导弹基地
In 2008, a remote Russian missile station
遭到攻击并被占领了一周
was overwhelmed and held for a week.
这个导弹基地被夺回时
When the station was retaken,
一个核弹头上的钚241少了0.75千克
241 on one warhead was three quarters of a kilo lighter.
丢失的钚241
The missing 241
14日在基辅歌剧院围攻时出现了
surfaced at the opera house siege in Kiev on the 14th.
转向
Coming about!
你有什么提议
What do you propose?
合作
Partnership.
我可不跟你合作
I wouldn't partner with you.
你身手了得  查不清底细
You can take care of yourself. You have no record.
训练有素还会隐匿踪迹
Someone in the arms trade, with training,
这样的军火商
who knows how to cover his tracks.
一点也不稀奇
Not that shocking.
不如说是特工
For an intelligence agent.
右转
Right!
去死吧  安德烈
Burn in hell, Andrei.
你不能这么驾驶
You can't jibe a boat like this!
不行也得行
You can if you have to.
-凯特  -你为什么不让他淹死
- Kat... - Why didn't you let him drown?
我需要他
I need him.
帮你卖武器吗
What, to sell guns?
我不是你想的那种人
I'm not who you think I am.
这我清楚
Well, that I know.
他给我看了那幅画
He showed me the drawing.
对不起  我必须接近他
I'm sorry. I had to get close to him.
你也许不清楚你丈夫是做什么的
I don't know what you think your husband does...
我们都清楚他是军火商
Oh, we both know he's an arms dealer.
他远不止如此
He's so much more.
那是什么
What, then?
安德烈·萨托尔掌握着全人类的性命
Andrei Sator holds all of our lives in his hands,
不止你一个
not just yours.
萨托尔先生要见你
Mr. Sator wants to see you.
好
Okay.
现在就去
Now.
他要我光着屁股去见他吗
He wants to see me without pants?
-相信我  -得了吧
- Trust me. - Save it.
我才不会上第二次当
I'm not falling for it twice.
你有更好的办法吗
You have a better option?
你为达成目的真是不择手段
Whatever it takes to get what you want.
丝毫没有考虑过我和我儿子
Not a second's thought for me or my son.
你觉得他现在会把我怎么样
What do you think he's gonna do to me now?
尽量别用
Try not to use it.
对谁都别用
On anyone.
行了
Enough.
看  我的心率和年轻人一样
See? Pulse of a man half my age.
陪我喝一杯
Drink with me.
看来我欠你一条命
It seems I now owe you my life.
不值一提
It's nothing.
我的命并非不值一提
My life is not nothing.
我也不喜欢亏欠别人
And I don't like to be in debt.
那就报答我
Then pay me.
不要报复你妻子
No retribution against your wife.
你以为是她解开了我的安全索吗
You think she released my harness?
是我自己疏忽大意
It was my own mistake.
那就帮我偷走钚241
Then help me steal the 241.
我需要资源  那是武器级别的钚
I need resources. It's weapons-grade plutonium.
意味着需要特殊手段  隔离设施...
That means special handling, containment facilities...
我很清楚
I know what it means.
我还需要你来教我辐射吗
You lecture me about radiation?
我安德烈·萨托尔
Andrei Sator,
十几岁就在家乡的废墟里挖钚了
digging plutonium from the rubble of my city as a teenager.
在哪里
Where?
斯达尔斯克12
Stalsk-12.
我的家乡
My home.
核弹头的一部分
One part of a warhead
在地面爆炸  其余的碎片四处散落
exploded at ground level, scattering the others.
他们需要人手来收集钚
They needed people to find the plutonium.
那是我的第一笔生意
It became my first contract.
没人跟我竞标  他们觉得那无异于送死
Nobody else even bid. They thought it was a death sentence.
但是
But...
安德烈·萨托尔
一些人眼里的死路
one man's probability of death...
就是其他人的活路
is another man's possibility for a life.
我在全新的俄罗斯获得了独家开采权
I staked my claim in the new Russia.
直至今日  也只有我的公司能在废墟中作业
Even now, my company is the only one to operate in the ruins.
钚241正经由北欧被运输到
The 241 is being transported through northern Europe,
第里雅斯特的一个长期核储存库
on its way to the long-term nuclear storage depot in Trieste.
我听说你在塔林有资源
I'm told you have resources in Tallinn.
今晚住下来
Stay with us tonight.
我坚持
I insist.
你想怎样
What do you want?
我们要谈谈今天的事
We're going to talk about today.
不谈
No, we're not.
不谈吗
No?
等着瞧吧
We'll see.
你休想用对待
Don't think for a second
其他那些女人的方式来对待我
you can treat me like you treat your other women.
那么
And, uh...
在你看来
how do you imagine...
我是怎么对待那些女人的
I treat these other women, huh?
你以为我强迫她们谈话吗
You think I force them into conversation?
你不想说话  没关系
You wanna be quiet, fine.
咬紧这个就行了
You can bite down on that.
就连你这种空虚易怒的人也需要得到回应
Even a soul as blank and brittle as yours needs a response.
恐惧和痛苦够不够  安德烈
Is fear and pain enough, Andrei?
我对你仅剩这些感觉了
That's all I have to offer you.
那也只好将就了
Well, that will have to do, then.
你为什么不肯放过我
Why didn't you just let me go?
因为
Because...
如果我无法拥有
if I can't have you...
谁也别想得到
no one else can.
你要是敢碰我  我就大声喊到他听见
And if you touch me, I scream so loud he hears.
你觉得我会允许他来干涉吗
You think I let him interfere?
要是他来了  你除了杀他别无他法
If he tried, you'd have to kill him.
那交易就黄了
End of deal.
所以你离我远点
So you leave me alone.
别来打扰
Not now!
心率98  发力后这样还不赖
Ninety-eight. Not bad for such exertion.
他在窗口偷看
He was at the window.
我只是好奇
I was curious.
你不该对我的钱财好奇
My property shouldn't concern you.
你是谁
Who are you?
你是怎么得知歌剧院一事的
How do you come by your information about the opera?
如果我不够机灵
You wouldn't do business with
你就不会跟我做生意了
someone who wasn't savvy enough to be recruited.
裂变材料市场的三分之二
Hell, the CIA provides two thirds
都是靠中情局支撑的
of the market for fissile material.
他们通常是买家  而非卖家
They're usually buying, not selling.
不过我们活在暮光之界
But we do live in a twilight world.
是惠特曼的吗  好诗
Is that Whitman? Pretty.
下次警告就是一枪爆头了
Next warning's a bullet in the brain.
不把我的蛋塞进我的喉咙了吗
No balls in my throat?
到了塔林就没时间
There will be no time for such things...
搞这种事了
in Tallinn.
你自己想办法过去  带上沃尔科夫
You make your way there. I want Volkov on your team.
不
No.
我把材料弄到手  你付我钱
I spring the material. You pay me off.
让你妻子来交易
Your wife does the exchange.
我从不让她插手生意
I never involve her in my business.
没错  所以我相信她
Yeah, that's why I trust her.
送他上岸
Put him ashore.
我怎么联系你
How do I contact you?
不用联系
You don't.
那你怎么付我定金
How do you advance me the funds?
拿到钚的时候可别手滑
Handle the plutonium better than that.
金条上有发现吗
What did you find on the gold?
没有印记  没有模具痕迹  毫无线索
No franks, no mold marks. Nothing.
-怎么会这样  -藏匿处
- How? - Dead drops.
他埋下时间胶囊  传递位置信息
He buries his time capsule, transmits the location,
之后再把他们送来的逆向物品挖出来
then digs it up to collect the inverted materials they sent.
瞬间就送到了  他会埋在哪里
Seemingly instantaneous. Where's he bury it?
几百年都不会被人发现的地方
Some place that won't be discovered for centuries.
土样显示是哪里
What did the soil samples show?
北欧  亚洲
Northern Europe, Asia.
有放射性
Radioactive.
从奥斯陆打捞上来的东西全都运来了
Everything salvaged from Oslo's been shipped here.
为什么带我来
Why am I here?
我不放心让其他人鉴定
I don't trust anyone else to assess the pieces.
运输车队经过市区  你怎么想
Via convoy through downtown, what's the thinking?
拥堵  交通模式不可预料
Crowded. Unpredictable traffic patterns.
几乎不可能设伏
It's almost impossible to plan an ambush.
他们的确聪明
They have a point.
车队有空中监控吗
Is the convoy monitored from the air?
有GPS定位  拐错一个弯  大部队就上
Tracked by GPS. One wrong turn, in come the cavalry.
我们需要重型武器
We need big guns.
不用开火就足以震慑对手
Guns that make the point without being fired.
还需要一辆低调的快车
We need a fast car that doesn't look fast.
四辆重型车辆  种类各不相同
Four heavy vehicles. All different.
公交  大巴  货车  而且必须有一辆消防车
Bus, coach, 18-wheeler. One of them has to be a fire truck.
关键在于  我们的准备要不留痕迹
Most of all, we have to set this up with nothing in the record.
电子或书面记录都不能有
Nothing electronic, nothing paper.
我不想得手后被萨托尔突袭
I don't want Sator ambushing us once we spring the material.
他不知情我们才安全
His ignorance is our only protection.
自由港
你看  凯特
You see, Kat?
这都是我最爱的枪
Some of my favorites.
被烧过  但还能用  不是吗
Singed but, uh, salvageable, wouldn't you say?
-这不在我的专业范畴内 -也是
- That's not my area of expertise. - Ah, that's right.
你不会和这种东西沾上边的
You would never have anything to do with such things.
可我们的生活正是在此产生了交集
But this is where our worlds collide.
什么意思  安德烈
What is this, Andrei?
你心知肚明  凯特
You know perfectly well what it is, Kat.
这肮脏的勾当
The filthy business
让你衣食无忧  供我们儿子上学
that put those clothes on your back and our boy in his school,
你还以为自己能脱得开干系
that you thought you could negotiate your way around.
车队十分钟后经过市区
该出发了
Time to go.
我不会跟他走的
I'm not going anywhere with him.
看着我
Look at me!
搞清楚
And understand,
你不能和猛虎谈条件
you don't negotiate with a tiger.
你只能崇拜猛虎  等它对付你时
You admire a tiger until he turns on you
你就会知道它的本性
and you feel its true fucking nature!
别过来
Don't.
待在原地
You stay right there.
绿队  倒计时两分钟
Green. Two minutes.
你不会杀我
You are not going to kill me.
我已经试过一次了
I already tried.
你把我推下了船
You pushed me off a boat.
但你不会冷血地向我开枪
You are not going to shoot me in cold blood.
我一点也不冷血  安德烈
My blood's not cold, Andrei.
是啊  可你还不够愤怒
No, but you're not angry enough.
结痂的愤怒只会变成绝望
Because anger scars over into despair.
我在你眼中
I look in your eyes...
只看到绝望
I see despair.
心存报复的贱人  傍着我生活
Vengeful bitch! Living off me!
还自觉高我一等
Thinking that you're better!
够了
Enough!
实时向我汇报情况
Tell me everything as it happens.
把这边锁起来
Seal me this side.
黄队  倒计时60秒
Yellow, 60 seconds.
60秒  确认
60. Check.
蓝队  倒计时45秒
Blue, 45 seconds.
蓝队  45秒  确认
Blue, 45, check.
好了  红队  我们朝你们过去了
Okay, Red. Coming to you.
三辆卡车就位
继续关注情况  把细节全都告诉我
Watch everything. Give me all the details.
都准备好了吗
All right, everyone set?
倒计时  五
And five...
四
four...
三
three...
二
two...
一
one.
黄队  上
Go, Yellow!
我们有麻烦了
We got a problem!
我们需要支援  该死
Backup, we need backup! Shit!
无线电中断了
他们还在继续移动吗
检查下无线电通话
Check the radio chatter.
每种武器级别的封装我都见过
I've seen samples of encapsulation in every weapons class.
但我没见过这种
This is not one of them.
这就是他想要的东西
That's what he's after.
我听不懂
Can't understand this.
你不是会爱沙尼亚语吗
You said you spoke Estonian.
这不是爱沙尼亚语
It's not Estonian.
这是逆向说的
It's backwards.
那边是什么情况
The hell is that?
快  快走
Go, go, go!
别给他
Don't give it to him.
这不是钚
This isn't plutonium.
这比钚更危险  该死的
It's worse than that, God damn it!
抱歉
Sorry.
他要逃走了
He's getting away.
他把她留在车里了
He left her in the car!
快追上她  快快快
Go after her, go! Go, go, go!
靠近点
Pull up alongside!
快  再近点
Come on, come on. Closer!
稳住  稳住
Keep it steady, keep it steady!
快点
Hurry up!
拜托
Please!
别动  我这就叫支援
All right, sit tight. I'm calling the cavalry.
什么支援
What cavalry?
如果你不说实话  她就会没命
If you are not telling the truth, she dies.
我不明白你在说什么
I don't know what you're talkin' about.
你把它留在了汽车里  而不是消防车上  对吗
You left it in the car, not the fire truck, right?
谁告诉你的
Who told you that?
快说  东西是不是在宝马车里
Just tell me now, is it really in the BMW?
我不知道
I don't know.
告诉我  否则我就再朝她开一枪
Tell me or I'll shoot her again!
你别把她扯进来
Leave her alone!
快杀了他
Kill him!
我没时间跟你讨价还价
I don't have time to negotiate.
-听我说  -三
- Listen to me! - Three.
我可以帮你
I can help you.
-救救我  -二
- Help me! - Two.
求你了
Please!
-不要  -一
- Don't! - One.
下颗子弹会打爆她的头
Next one's a bullet to the head.
-不  -一
- No! - One.
二  三
Two. Three.
好吧  好吧
Okay! Okay.
在汽车里
The car.
我把它留在宝马车里了
The BMW. I left it in the BMW.
我们会去确认你所言是否为实
We're going to check this is real.
东西在杂物箱里
It's in the glove box!
你把东西放在哪了
Where did you leave it?
在汽车里  还是在消防车里
Car or fire truck, which one?
你把它放在哪辆车里了
Which vehicle did you leave it in?
我出去之前要问清楚
I need to know before I go out there.
我已经告诉你了
I already told you.
我相信你
I believe you.
是你要她来的  这下满意了吧
You wanted her here, I hope you'll be happy...
安全
Clear!
惠勒  去检查另一边
Wheeler, go check the other side.
你们俩跟我来
You two.
他去哪了
Where did he go?
过去
The past.
东西在杂物箱里
It's in the glove box!
我们会去确认你所言是否为实
We're going to check this is real.
-三  二  一  -好吧  好吧
- Three, two, one. - Okay, okay...
下颗子弹会打爆她的头
Next one's a bullet to the head.
-不  不  -一
- No! No! - One.
-听我说  -二
- Listen to me. - Two.
三
Three.
-我可以帮你  -我没时间跟你讨价还价
- I can help you. - I don't have time to negotiate.
告诉我  否则我就再朝她开一枪
Tell me or I'll shoot her again.
你别把她扯进来
Leave her alone!
快说  东西是不是在宝马车里
Tell me now, is it really in the BMW?
我不知道
I don't know.
你把它留在了汽车里  而不是消防车上  对吗
You left it in the car, not the fire truck, right?
谁告诉你的
Who told you that?
如果你不说实话  她就会没命
If you're not telling the truth, she dies.
我不明白你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
-医护兵  -报到
- Medic! - Check in.
她中枪了吗
She's been shot?
把她带回这边
Bring her back, this side.
她是被逆向子弹打伤的吗
Was she shot with an inverted round?
这是艾夫斯  他是我们的人
This is Ives. He's one of us.
"我们"  这些人到底是谁
"Us"! Who are these guys?
普丽娅的人  我们的人
Priya's. Ours.
萨托尔怎么会知道我们的伏击计划
How did Sator know about the ambush?
未来的人知道
It's posterity.
在马路中间伏击  不可能不留下记录
An ambush in the middle of the street can't stay out of the records.
放屁  他对我们的每一步都了如指掌  每一步
Bullshit! He knew every move we made! Every one of 'em.
肯定有人泄密了  到底是谁
Somebody talked. Who was it?
-是你吗  -不是
- Was it you? - No. No.
在每个阶段  你都知道得太多了
At every stage, you've known too much.
我再问你一遍
I'm going to ask you again.
是不是你泄密了
Did you talk?
没人泄密
Nobody talked.
他们在进行时间钳形行动
They're running a temporal pincer movement.
什么行动
A what?
钳形行动  但不是在地形上  而是在时间中
The pincer movement. But not in space, in time.
一半人顺着时间正向前进
Half his team moves forward through the event.
他会监视他们  然后从终点逆向袭击
He monitors them, and then attacks at the end moving backwards,
对一切了如指掌
knowing everything.
除了我藏钚的地方
Except for where I stashed the plutonium.
那并不是钚  对吗
Which isn't really plutonium, is it?
我告诉过你了  那就是他想要的东西
I told you it was what he was after.
而你就这么告诉他了
And you just told him where it was.
我骗了他
I lied.
天啊  你居然骗了他
Jesus. You lied about it?
他在房间里无法核实
He couldn't verify inside the room.
他无论如何都会朝她开枪
He'd have shot her anyway.
说谎是标准行动手段
Lying is standard operating procedure.
伤口扩散太大
It's spread too far.
什么意思
Meaning what?
她要死了
She's gonna die.
标准行动手段
Standard operating procedure.
你们不能救她吗  我们有什么能做的吗
Can't you help her? Can we do something?
我们可不可以通过逆转她来逆转辐射
Can't we stabilize the inverse radiation by inverting the patient?
那要花好几天
Takes days.
赶快行动吧
Let's go.
我们几分钟前才拿下这台机器
We took control of this machine minutes ago.
之前是萨托尔的机器
Before that, it's Sator's.
她在这边还能活多久
How long is she gonna live on this side?
最多三小时
Three hours, tops.
我要带她过去
I'm taking her through.
我不会眼看着她死  我愿意冒险
I'm not gonna let her die. I'll take my chances.
我们没法让你回来
There's no way of bringing you back.
我们再找一台机器
We find another machine.
一周之前吗  哪里去找
A week ago? Where?
奥斯陆
Oslo.
那台机器在机场安保内部
That facility's inside an airport security perimeter.
那里固若金汤
It's impregnable.
但上周情况可不一样
It wasn't last week.
我们去意已决
We're going in.
你不妨帮帮我们
You might as well help us.
这是检验窗
This is a proving window.
当你走向旋转门时
As you approach the turnstile,
如果你没在检验窗里看到自己
if you don't see yourself in the proving window,
那就别进去
do not enter the machine.
为什么
Why not?
如果你没看到自己从另一边反向出去
If you don't see yourself reverse-exit a machine,
那就代表你出不去了
then you ain't getting out.
-这方法有用吗  -有用
- Is that gonna work? - Yeah.
你自己看吧
See for yourself.
这就是你要的答案  走吧
There's your answer. Let's go.
她的伤势在逐渐稳定
She's stabilizing slowly.
我会清理并缝合伤口  恢复需要时间
I'll clean and close, but the rest is time.
多久才能恢复
How long does she need?
起码四五天  最好一周
Four, five days. A week to be sure.
尼尔  想办法去奥斯陆
Hey, Neil. Find a way to get us to Oslo.
我要回去
I'm going back out there.
回去干什么
To do what?
阻止萨托尔带着我给他的那东西逃走
To stop Sator from getting away with whatever it is I just gave him.
你没给他  你骗了他
You didn't. You lied about where it was.
等等
Wait.
你回去是为了她
You're going out there for her.
他威胁说要在过去杀了她
He threatened to kill her in the past.
如果他做到了  那现在的她会怎样
If he does, what happens to her here?
这就无从得知了
That's unknowable.
如果你去过去做出改变
If you're there to make a change,
就无法在现在看到结果
you're not here to observe its effect.
那你怎么认为
What do you believe?
发生过的事已经发生了
What's happened's happened.
我们必须在此时此刻救她
We need to save her, here and now.
如果你回去
If you go back out there,
你可能会把他想要的东西拱手相送
you might hand him exactly what he's after.
别让他们把她带回去
Don't let them take her back through there.
-好吗  -此地不宜久留
- Okay? - We can't stay here.
我们没多少时间了
We don't have a lot of time.
你不如去找个去找个舒适的集装箱
So why don't you find us a nice, cozy shipping container
刚从奥斯陆来的船上卸下来的那种
that's just come off a ship from Oslo?
真会逞能
This is cowboy shit.
你根本不知道穿过那道门后
You have no idea what you're getting yourself into
会有什么在等着你
if you go through that door.
反正我去意已决  你不如给点提示好了
Well, I'm going, so any tips would be welcome.
惠勒  跟他说说
Wheeler, brief him.
你需要自备空气
You'll need your own air.
正常的空气无法穿过逆时间的肺膜
Regular air won't pass through the membranes of inverted lungs.
首要原则
Number one rule:
不要接触正时间的自己
don't come into contact with your forward self.
所以需要用到这些挡板和防护服
It's the whole point of these barriers and protective suits.
我们没时间了
We don't have time.
如果你们的粒子接触上了...
Well, if your particles come into contact...
就会怎样
What?
你会湮灭
Annihilation.
那就糟糕了  是吧
That would be bad, right?
从气闸舱出来后  先缓缓  适应一下
When you exit the air lock, take a moment to orient yourself.
你会觉得周遭的事物很奇怪
Things will feel strange.
你跑的时候  风会在你背后吹
When you run, the wind will be at your back.
碰到火  你的衣服会结冰
You encounter fire, ice will form on your clothes
因为热量会逆向传导
as the transfer of heat is reversed.
引力会照常存在  但你会觉得
Gravity will feel normal but appear reversed
周围的世界都是颠倒的
for the world around you.
你的视觉和听觉可能会失真
You may experience distortions in your vision and hearing.
这是正常现象
This is normal.
-我能开车吗  -真会逞能
- Can I drive a car? - Cowboy shit.
我不敢打包票
I can't vouch for the handling.
摩擦力和风阻也是反向的
Friction and wind resistance are reversed.
你人是逆向的  但这世界不是
You are inverted. The world is not.
发信器装在箱子上了吗
Was the transponder on the case?
我们把那个箱子扔了
We've tossed that case.
我要往回走  那是我的目标
I'm moving backwards. It's the ball I have to follow.
把收信器给我
Give me the reader.
好
Okay.
准备好了吗
You ready?
追踪中
材料不在箱子里
The material's not in the case.
把算法的其他部分送去爆炸源
Get the other sections of the algorithm to the hypocenter.
他骗了我们
He was lying.
东西不在宝马车里
It wasn't in the BMW.
那在哪里
So, where is it?
我看到了交接
I saw the handoff.
你让我白白打了她一枪
You made me shoot her for nothing.
不过你是头一个让我心率超过130的人
You did get my pulse above 130, no one's done that before.
连我妻子都做不到
Not even my wife.
你给艾夫斯他们留了好大一个烂摊子
You left Ives and his team a hell of a cleanup.
热传导也逆转了
Heat transfer was reversed.
你可能是史上第一个因汽油爆炸
You might be the first case of hypothermia
而导致体温过低的人
from a gasoline explosion in history.
我已经见怪不怪了
At this point, nothing surprises.
我们这是回奥斯陆吗
We're headed back to Oslo?
我们在一个罗塔斯的集装箱里
In a Rotas shipping container.
他拿到材料了  尼尔
He's got the material, Neil.
我拱手送给了他
I handed it to him on a plate.
我警告过你
I warned you...
发生过的事已经发生了
What's happened's happened.
我现在明白了
I get it now.
但我很难信任一个
But it's hard to take things on trust
说话半真半假的人
from people speaking half-truths.
你这么说不公平
That's not fair.
我们认识之前你就参与其中了
You were a part of this before we met.
你之前是普丽娅的手下吗
Were you working for Priya?
不是
No.
那是谁招募的你  尼尔
Who recruited you, Neil?
现在知道对你没有任何好处
It can't possibly do you any good to know that right now.
等这次行动结束
When this is over,
如果我们还活着  你也还在意的话
if we're still standing, and you still care,
我就把人生故事和盘托出  好吗
then you can hear my life story, okay?
抱歉我把你卷了进来
I'm sorry I involved you.
你得告诉我这是怎么回事
You need to tell me what's going on.
这位尼尔知道的比我更多
Apparently Neil here knows more about it than I do.
好运  伙计
Good luck, pal.
只要告诉凯特
By telling Kat anything,
她就会被普丽娅盯上
we're compromising her in Priya's eyes.
她早就被普丽娅盯上了
In Priya's eyes, she's already compromised.
她可能会死  她有权知道缘由
She has the right to know why she might die.
我会死吗
Am I gonna die?
我们会想办法阻止的
Not if we have something to say about it.
没错
And we do.
你是谁
Who are you?
先从简单的概念说起  每一条物理定律...
Let's start with the simple stuff. Every law of physics...
材料不在箱子里
The material's not in the case.
把算法的其他部分送去爆炸源
Get the other sections of the algorithm to the hypocenter.
你受伤了吗
You injured?
算法是什么  尼尔
What's the algorithm, Neil?
钚241是算法的一部分  一共有九个部分
241 is one section of it. One out of nine.
它是一条以实体存在的程式
It's a formula rendered into physical form
因此无法被复制或传递
so it can't be copied or communicated.
它是只有一个功能的黑匣子
It's a black box with one function.
什么功能
Which is?
逆转时序  但对象不是物体或人
Inversion. But not objects or peoples.
而是我们的世界
The world around us.
我不明白
I don't understand.
他们逆转越来越多的物体的熵之后
As they invert the entropy of more and more objects,
两个方向的时间愈发缠绕交织
the two directions of time are becoming more intertwined.
但整体时间还是向我们的方向流动
But because the environment essentially flows in our direction...
我们是主流
we dominate.
逆时间就是逆流而行
They're always swimming upstream.
你也因此得救
It's what saved your life.
逆时间爆炸要与整体时间对抗
Inverted explosion was pushing against the environment.
就像迎风撒尿
Pissing in the wind.
而这个算法可以改变风向
And the algorithm can change the direction of that wind.
逆转整个世界的熵
It can invert the entropy of the world.
那会怎样
And if that happens?
没戏唱了
End of play.
"没戏唱了"  你能把话说清楚吗
"End of play." Can you be a little more precise?
万物生灵  都会在瞬间毁灭
Everyone and everything that's ever lived, destroyed. Instantly.
够清楚了吧
Precise enough?
包括我儿子
Including my son.
多休息才能快速恢复
The more you sleep, the faster you'll heal.
上卡车了
On a truck.
应该快到了
Shouldn't be long now.
我一直在想
I've been thinking.
我们是他们的祖先
We're their ancestors.
如果他们毁灭了我们  不也毁灭了自己吗
If they destroy us, won't that destroy them?
这就谈到"祖父悖论"了
This brings us to the grandfather paradox.
什么悖论
The what?
如果你回到过去
If you went back in time
杀了你的祖父
and killed your own grandfather,
那你是如何出生去杀他的呢
how could you have been born to commit the act?
答案是什么
What's the answer?
没有答案  这是个悖论
There's no answer. It's a paradox.
但在未来
But in the future,
那些掌权者认为
those in power clearly believe that you can
他们能把祖父踢下楼梯
kick grandpa down the stairs,
挖他的眼睛
gouge his eyes out,
割他的喉咙
slit his throat,
而不会导致任何后果
without consequence.
他们是对的吗
Could they be right?
这不重要
Doesn't matter.
他们相信这一点
They believe it.
所以他们甘愿毁灭我们
So they're willing to destroy us.
我能接着睡了吗
Can I go back to sleep now?
不  我想的是另一件事
No. I thought of something else.
这下好了
Great.
时间的逆流
This reversing the flow of time.
我们此刻在这里是不是就意味着他们没能得逞
Doesn't us being here now mean it never happens?
因为我们阻止了他们
That we stop them?
乐观来说  你可能是对的
Optimistically, I'd say that's right.
悲观来说呢
Pessimistically?
以平行世界理论来说  我们无从得知
In a parallel worlds theory, we can't know the relationship
意识与多重现实的关系
between consciousness and multiple realities.
听起来很头疼吧
Does your head hurt yet?
是的
Yes.
去睡吧
Try to sleep.
该死
Shit.
卡车没开进去
They didn't take us inside.
怎么办
What do we do?
利用破口进去
We use the breach.
趁着撞击后的混乱  准备好
The chaos right after impact. Get ready.
她恢复得怎么样
She healed enough?
我说不好
I don't know.
我从没做过这种事
I've never done this before.
消防队到了
The fire crew's there.
你带凯特从破口进去
You take Kat through the breach,
我对付萨托尔的人  控制保险库
I take care of Sator's men and secure the vault.
然后你带她进来
Then you bring her in.
你的胳膊怎么样
How's your arm?
不太好
Not good.
听到引擎的声音就行动
We move as soon as we hear the engines.
-等等  等等  -怎么了
- Hold on, hold on. - What?
你在流血
You're bleeding.
来  让我看看
All right, let me take a look at it.
准备好了吗
Ready?
在这等着  我进去了
Wait here. I'm going in.
快啊
Come on!
走走走
Go, go, go!
快走
Go!
你知道从保险库里出来的人是我
You knew it was me coming out of that vault.
你怎么不说
Why didn't you say?
你当时正准备
That's a lot of explaining
一枪崩了自己  没时间解释
when someone's about to put a bullet in their own brain.
事后可以说啊
But afterwards?
反正都一样  我知道你不会有事
Thing's the same, I knew you'd be okay.
发生过的事已经发生了
What's happened's happened.
如果我告诉你之后  你改变做法呢
If I told you and you acted differently,
谁说得准
who knows?
原则是隐瞒不说
The policy is to suppress.
谁的原则
Whose policy?
我们的  朋友
Ours, my friend.
我们是拯救可能毁灭的世界的人
We're the people saving the world from what might've been.
凯特
Kat?
我在
I'm here.
会留下不小的伤疤
It'll be quite a scar.
但你没事了
You'll be okay.
成功了
Did it.
哪里成功了
You did what?
安德烈拿到了算法
Andrei has the algorithm.
你们不知道他在哪里
You don't know where he is.
或在什么时间
Or when.
-让普丽娅来奥斯陆  -为什么
- Get Priya here to Oslo. - Why?
我按兵不动的话  两天后
If I don't do something, in two days,
她会告诉我钚241的事
she tells me about the 241.
那是无法改变的
Nothing can change that.
等着瞧吧
We'll see.
让她过来就行
Just get her here.
你好  普丽娅
Hello, Priya.
怎么回事
What's going on?
尼尔人呢
Where's Neil?
他在照料凯瑟琳·巴顿  她差点被你害死
Nursing Katherine Barton, who almost died because of you.
跟我有关吗
What did I do?
跟你即将要做的事有关
It's what you're going to do.
两天后  你会让我拿钚241
In two days, you're gonna have me dangle plutonium-241
去引诱世界上最危险的军火商
in front of the world's most dangerous arms dealer.
我想知道为什么
Now, I wanna know why.
你让萨托尔拿到钚241了
You let Sator get hold of 241?
不  我让他拿到了算法
No, I let him get ahold of the algorithm.
跟我说说这个算法  普丽娅
So, tell me about it, Priya.
它是独一无二的
It's... It's unique.
发明这个算法的科学家自杀了
The scientist who built it took her own life
因为她不想受迫再造出一个来
so she couldn't be forced to make another.
未来的科学家吗
A scientist in the future?
许多代人之后的未来
Generations from now.
她为什么非自杀不可
Why does she have to kill herself?
你熟悉曼哈顿计划吗
You're familiar with the Manhattan Project?
美国陆军部研制原子弹的计划
他们在临近第一次原子弹试爆时
As they approached the first atomic test,
奥本海默开始担心
Oppenheimer became concerned
爆炸会引发一系列的连锁反应
that the detonation might produce a chain reaction,
吞没整个世界
engulfing the world.
他们还是试爆了  所幸成功了
They went ahead anyway and got lucky.
把这位科学家看作她那个时代的奥本海默
Think of our scientist as her generation's Oppenheimer.
她精巧构设了一个逆转世界的方法
She devises a method for inverting the world,
但却坚信如果毁灭我们
but becomes convinced that by destroying us,
就会毁灭他们自己
they're destroying themselves.
也就是祖父悖论
The grandfather paradox.
但是  和奥本海默不同
But, unlike Oppenheimer,
她反抗了
she rebels,
将算法分割为九个部分
splitting the algorithm into nine sections
将它们藏在她能想到的最合适的地方
and hiding them the best place she can think of.
藏在了过去
The past.
这个时代
Here, now.
九个有核国家
There are nine nuclear powers.
九枚炸弹
Nine bombs.
九组这个世界有史以来
Nine sets of the most closely guarded materials
最为严加看守的材料
in the history of the world.
最佳的藏匿地点
The best hiding place possible.
保障核安全的设施
Nuclear containment facilities.
萨托尔毕生的使命
Sator's lifelong mission,
由未来的人资助和指引
financed and guided by the future, has been to
就是找出并重组算法
find and reassemble the algorithm.
他们为什么选了他
Why do they choose him?
因为他在合适的时间出现在了合适的地点
Because he was at the right place at the right time.
苏联解体
The collapse of the Soviet Union.
是核武器有史以来最为危险的时刻
The most insecure moment in the history of nuclear weapons.
他拿到了算法的几个部分
How many sections does he have?
拿到钚241之后  就集齐了
After the 241, all nine.
我的天
Jesus Christ.
所以这一次你要改变行事的策略
And that's why you're going to do things differently this time.
改变策略
To change things?
为了保护凯瑟琳吗
So Katherine won't get hurt?
为了阻止萨托尔得到算法
So Sator won't get the algorithm.
即便那个世界真的存在
If that universe can exist...
也与我们无缘
we don't live in it.
我们试试
Well, let's try.
这次你要提醒我
You're going to warn me.
我不会的
No, I'm not.
-无知是我们的武器  -拜托
- Ignorance is our ammunition. - Come on.
如果你之前知道算法是什么
If you had known what the algorithm was,
还会让它落入萨托尔之手吗
would you have let it fall into Sator's hands?
你想让萨托尔拿到算法的最后一部分
You want Sator to get the last section.
只有这样他才会拿出其它八个部分
That is the only way he'll bring together the other eight.
所以我就该偷走钚241
I was supposed to steal it...
然后又失手于萨托尔吗
then lose it?
任务完成
Mission accomplished.
你利用了我
You used me.
就像你利用了凯瑟琳
As you used Katherine.
标准行动手段
Standard operating procedure.
你的使命完成了
You've done your part.
完成了
My part?
我是这个任务的主角
I'm the protagonist of this operation.
你
You...
只是主角之一
are a protagonist.
你以为只有你才能拯救世界吗
Did you think you were the only one capable of saving the world?
不是
No.
但确实只有我
But I am.
因为我还没告诉你
Because I haven't told you
他将会在何时何地重组算法
where he's assembling the algorithm or when.
你马上就会告诉我
You're about to.
不  我不会告诉你
No, I'm not.
除非你让我们加入
So, deal us in.
"我们"
"Us"?
你为什么还要把她扯进来
Why would you want to involve her again?
因为她能接近萨托尔
Because she can get close to him.
他还信任她吗
Does he still trust her?
他以为她死了
He thinks she's dead.
但他过去是信任她的
But he used to.
你开始以全新的方式看待世界了
You have started looking at the world in a new way.
现在轮到你了
And now, it's your turn.
假设她能活下来
Assuming she makes it out alive,
就算你认为她知道得太多了  也要放过她
whether or not you feel she knows too much.
我做不到
I can't.
如果你无权做主
If you don't have the authority,
那就去请示负责解决后患的人
then talk to whoever's in charge of loose ends.
我需要你保证
I need your word
她和她儿子的人身安全  普丽娅
that she and her son will be safe, Priya.
干我们这行的  保证有什么用
What good is someone's word in our line of business?
我保证他们的安全
They'll be safe.
特隆赫姆海岸有一个集合点
There's a rally point offshore at Trondheim.
你们想办法过去
Get yourselves up there.
艾夫斯的小队准备要逆转了
Ives has a team ready to invert.
你们也有旋转门
You have a turnstile?
正是我们要毁掉的技术
The exact technology that we're trying to suppress.
以毒攻毒是很危险的
Fighting fire with fire's a treacherous business.
但未来有些人
But there are some people, in the future,
想要将算法的存在延续到过去
who want to continue the algorithm's journey into the past.
要知道
You see...
信条不是在过去创立的
Tenet wasn't founded in the past.
而是在未来
It will be founded in the future.
真不习惯鸟倒着飞
Can't get over the birds.
你感觉如何
How're you feeling?
告诉我你会杀了他
Tell me you're gonna kill him.
我不能杀他
I can't.
为什么
Why not?
你肯定杀过不少人
Bet you've probably killed a lot of people.
可不能杀有死亡开关的人
Not with a dead man's switch.
就是他戴的那个运动手环
The fitness tracker he wears.
他很在乎自己的健康
He's obsessive about his health.
运动手环连接着开关
It'll be linked to a switch,
很可能只是简单的电子邮件触发
probably a simple e-mail burst
一旦他的心跳停止  就会触发邮件
that reveals the location of the dead drop,
透露藏匿处的位置
set to fire if his heart stops.
他的死亡会激活算法
His death activates the algorithm.
他死了  世界就会毁灭
He dies, the world ends.
没人敢杀他
No one dares kill him.
不  你们没弄明白
No, you've missed the point.
他打算自我了断
He's intending to end his life.
为什么
Why?
他快死了
He's dying.
无法手术的胰腺癌
Inoperable pancreatic cancer.
他要拉全世界陪葬
And he's taking the world with him.
如果他无法拥有  谁也别想得到
If he can't have her, no one can.
他能选择世界毁灭的时间和地点
He gets to choose the time and place for the end of the world.
他会怎么选
What moment? What does he choose?
你说过有一次度假  你让他感受到爱了
You told me about a holiday where you let him feel loved.
在越南
Vietnam.
你说他不见踪影  是哪天
You said he vanished. What day?
我和麦克斯上岸后他就飞走了
I went ashore with Max and he flew off,
但我不记得日期
but I don't know what day it was.
是14日  十天前
It was the 14th. Ten days ago.
他在乌克兰
He was in Ukraine.
基辅歌剧院的围攻行动
At the Kiev opera siege.
你怎么知道的
How do you know about that?
关键是  他不在游艇上  那就是他的时间空档
The point is, he wasn't on his yacht, so that's his window.
回到那个黄金时刻  作为他生命的终点
To go back to that golden moment and have it be his last.
全人类的终点
Everyone's last.
我们得在萨托尔不知道的情况下
We have to lift the algorithm from the dead drop
把算法从藏匿点偷出来
without Sator knowing.
如果他认为算法还藏在那里  他就会自杀
If he believes it's there, he kills himself.
而我们不会陪葬
And not the rest of us.
藏匿点在哪里
Where's the dead drop?
没人能知道全部  朋友
Knowledge divided, my friend.
你不打算告诉我吗
You're not gonna tell me?
无知是我们的武器
Ignorance is our ammunition.
不过我需要你回到游艇上  凯特
But I need you back on that yacht, Kat.
为什么
Why?
你需要在我们把算法从藏匿点偷出来之前
You have to stop him killing himself until we know the algorithm
阻止他自杀
is out of the dead drop.
但如果我被揭穿  我儿子会目睹一切
But if I'm caught there, my son sees.
我不希望他生命的最后时刻
I don't want those moments to be full of anguish
心中充满痛苦
if they're gonna be his last.
不会的
They're not.
时间到了
It's time.
我们准备逆时间返回14日
We're working our way back to the 14th,
但是如果不知道藏匿点在哪里
but without knowing where the dead drop is,
我能做的准备非常有限
there's only so much I can do to prepare.
你知道爆炸源是什么吗
You know what a hypocenter is?
是地下核试验的引爆点
It's ground zero for an underground nuclear test.
迈克尔·克罗斯比爵士告诉我
Sir Michael Crosby told me about
14日在斯达尔斯克12有一次核试爆
a detonation in Stalsk-12 on the 14th.
爆炸源底部就是藏匿点
The dead drop is at the bottom of the hypocenter.
那次爆炸会把算法封在地底
That explosion seals up the algorithm.
那我们最好在爆炸之前
Well, then we better pull it out of that hole
把算法偷出来  对吧
before the bomb goes off, eh?
列队
Line it up.
向前
Move forward.
下一位
Next.
列队
Line it up.
尼尔呢
Where's Neil?
他一定是先过去了
He must've gone through already.
我还没跟他道别
I didn't get to say goodbye.
这就是最后一面了吧
This is goodbye, isn't it?
我想告诉你
I'd like to say...
你不是非得这么做  凯特
that you don't have to do this, Kat...
安德烈对我做的最过分的事  就是向我提出条件
Worst thing Andrei ever did to me was that offer he made me.
如果我同意不再见儿子就放过我
Let me go if I agreed never to see my son again.
我大喊大叫
I shouted and...
咒骂他
swore.
但他从我脸上看出来了  虽然只有一瞬
But he'd seen it on my face, just for an instant.
我曾考虑接受
I considered it.
我不清楚我是恨他的所作所为
I don't know if I hate him more for what he's done,
还是恨他看透了我
or because he knows that about me.
这是拯救我孩子的机会
A chance to help save my child.
你不知道这对一个母亲来说有多重要
You can't know what that means to a mother.
是的
No.
你以前杀过你恨的人
You've killed people you've hated before.
通常不是为了报仇
It's not usually personal.
反正他也快死了  也许不算是杀人
Well, he's dying anyway. Maybe it doesn't even count.
杀人就是杀人  凯特
It always counts, Kat.
你不是去杀他的  你是后备方案
You're not there to kill him, you're the backstop.
如果他在我们偷出算法之前自杀
If we don't lift that algorithm and he kills himself,
全人类都要给他陪葬
he takes us all with him.
你做好该做的就行了
You just keep up your end, okay?
今天是14日
Today's the 14th.
西伯利亚海岸
Offshore of Siberia.
我们该出发了
Time for us to go.
你往回多走一天
You keep going back another day,
给自己足够的时间返回越南
give you some time to get back into Vietnam.
谁送我上游艇
And who gets me on the yacht?
我安排好人选了
I've got somebody good lined up.
等尘埃落定  你自己抚养孩子  带上这个
When it's over, when you're raising your boy, carry this.
如果什么时候你感到有危险
There may be a time and place you feel threatened.
按下通话键  报上你的位置  然后挂断
Hit "talk," state your location, hang up.
电话打给谁
Who gets the message?
未来的人
Posterity.
斯达尔斯克12
Stalsk-12.
这是个与世隔绝的城市  什么都可能发生
Hidden from the world is a city where anything can happen.
就在今天  女士们先生们
And today, ladies and gents,
你们将在十分钟的时间内体会
for ten minutes, it most assuredly does.
你们被分成了两队
You've been divided into two teams
开展时间钳形行动
for a temporal pincer movement.
我们是红队  顺时间行动
We're Red Team, moving forward.
为了区分两队  你们要带上这个
In order to distinguish the teams, you'll wear these.
那边的朋友们  他们是蓝队
Our friends over there, Blue Team,
由惠勒中校带领  逆时间行动
led by Commander Wheeler, are inverted.
为什么不让我们看到他们
Why don't they let us see them?
也许我们没有好结果
Maybe we won't like what happened.
一小时后  他们开了同样的作战会议
One hour from now, they had this briefing.
然后空降在爆炸源上方的山脊
Then, were dropped on the ridge above the hypocenter,
尽量接近引爆的时间
as close in time to the detonation as possible.
他们的任务是清扫障碍
Their objectives were clearance and clarification.
我们的作战会议得益于他们的经验
Now, this briefing has the benefit of their experience.
两队都有倒计时手表
Both teams have countdown watches.
我们的手表空降后倒计时十分钟
Ours counts down from ten, from landing
到零时爆炸发生
to zero to the explosion.
蓝队与之相反
Blue Team is reversed.
如果到零时还没到空降区
If you are not at the LZ at zero,
你就回不来了
you are not leaving.
明白了吗
Do you understand?
我们空降后  控制空降区让蓝队撤离
We drop in, clear LZs for Blue Team evacuation.
我们进入城市
We make our way into the city proper.
这些都是废弃建筑
These buildings are abandoned,
但我们得知  这里也有一道旋转门
but we learned there is a turnstile.
可能会遭到双向时间反击
Expect a bitemporal response.
他们有逆时间武器吗
They'll have inverse ordnance?
逆时间的  常规的
Inverse, conventional,
正向对手  逆向对手  他们都有
forward antagonists, inverted antagonists, they have it all.
在城市的另一边
On the other side of the city,
沿着山坡爬上去可以到达爆炸源
the ground rises to the ridge above the hypocenter.
小分队将从市区走这条通道
A splinter unit will take this tunnel from the city
到达山洞里的爆炸源
to the floor of the hypocenter.
蓝队在这里发现了一个入口
Blue Team located an entrance here.
核弹在石壁中
The bomb is in this rock,
在山洞上方爆炸造成坍塌
high above, to trigger a collapse,
封死山洞
sealing the cavern.
我们怎么拆除那么高的核弹
How do we defuse the bomb up there?
不用拆除  核弹会按计划引爆
We don't. The explosion takes place as planned.
我们的任务就是拆弹失败
Now, our job is to fail to defuse that bomb
掩护小分队神不知鬼不觉地完成任务
while the splinter unit achieves its task undetected.
什么任务
Which is?
保密信息  你不需要知道
Need-to-know, and you don't.
还有谁要问蠢问题
Any other stupid questions?
好  走吧  准备出发
Good. Well, let's go. Let's get ready.
我要第一波行动
I wanted to be on the first wave.
没有什么第一波
There is no first wave.
红队和蓝队同时行动
Red Team and Blue Team operate simultaneously.
如果你跳不出线性思维
Look, don't get on the chopper
就别上直升机了
if you can't stop thinking in linear terms.
你想加入偷出容器内容物的队伍吗
Now, you wanna be on the team that lifts the contents of the capsule?
没错
Absolutely.
那就是我们
Yeah, that's us.
我们就是小分队
We're splinter unit.
就我们俩
Just us?
知道容器里装了什么的人不能活着离开
No one who knows the contents of that capsule can leave the field.
有我们俩就够了
I thought we'd manage ourselves.
甲板离水面有12米
It's 40 feet from the private deck to the water.
你敢跳吗
Can you jump it?
一跃而下
I can dive it.
在我发信号之前别让他死
Until you see my signal, you don't let him die.
还有30秒
Thirty seconds!
上  上  上
Go! Go! Go!
我们要遭遇冲击波了
We're coming in on a shockwave.
大家抓稳
Hang on, people.
站起来
On your feet!
那边
There!
夫人  您不是上岸了吗
Ma'am. We thought you'd gone ashore.
我溜回来给安德烈一个惊喜
Well, I snuck back to surprise Andrei.
老板已经走了
The boss left.
请萨托尔来这里找我
Well, have Mr. Sator find me here.
别告诉其他人
And don't tell the others.
我来打扫
I'll get the mess.
有地雷
Mines!
他们说你上岸了
They told me you'd gone ashore.
他们说你飞走了
They told me you'd flown off.
我回来看你和麦克斯
I came back to see you and Max.
安娜陪麦克斯上岸了
Max is on shore with Anna.
刚才的事  我们得单独谈谈
We need time, just you and me, after what happened.
我开玩笑的  我犯糊涂了
I was joking. It was a stupid joke.
你认为我这个母亲不称职
You think I'm a terrible mother.
我们都清楚你更厌恶我
We both know my opinion of you is higher than yours of me.
我想重归于好  安德烈
I want things to be better, Andrei.
找掩护
Take cover!
给我反坦克火箭筒
Get me a goddamn AT4!
快干掉他
Take him out, now!
打掩护
Provide some cover!
上上上  我们走
Move, move, move! Let's go!
上上上
Move, move, move!
惠勒
Wheeler!
过来
Get outta there!
快
Come on!
艾夫斯
Ives!
小分队  那边
Splinter unit. Here.
今晚的日落一定很美
You know, it's going to be a beautiful sunset.
我派人接麦克斯回来
I'll get Max brought back.
我们应该和他一起看日落
We should share the moment with him.
我给你倒杯酒
I'll make you a drink.
把我儿子接回船上
Bring my son back to the boat.
没时间了  我们走
We're runnin' out of time, let's go!
如果被发现  就功亏一篑了
If they see us, it's all for nothing.
我们得声东击西
We need a distraction.
放心吧
Don't worry about that.
听我命令
On my mark!
火箭炮  轰炸底层
RPG, hit the base!
听我口令  轰炸大楼
That building on my mark!
三  二
Three! Two!
一  开火
One! Fire!
开火
Fire!
上  上
Move! Move!
没有回头路了  走
We're committed now. Come on.
那是什么
What's that?
我跟中情局借来的
I borrowed it from the CIA.
是什么东西
What is it?
毁灭世界的方法
The way the world ends.
不是惊天巨响  而是一声呜咽
Not with a bang, but a whimper.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我吞下它  一切就结束了
When I take this, it's all over.
那就先别吞
Then don't take it yet.
为什么
Why not?
因为我们还要看日落
Because we have the sunset coming.
伏特加也没喝完
And a little vodka left.
麦克斯也快回来了
And Max will be here soon.
他们说陪麦克斯上岸的
They said they thought it was you,
不是安娜  而是你
not Anna, ashore with Max.
只要你分得清我是谁就行
So long as you can tell the difference.
稍等一下  亲爱的
A moment's business, my love.
马希尔  能收到吗
Mahir, do you copy?
还不行  重复一遍  还不行
Not clear. I repeat, not clear!
收到
Copy that.
重复一遍  还不行
I repeat, not clear!
尼尔
Neil!
上
Go!
我们没有能炸开这门的炸药
We don't have anything big enough to blow this.
找找他身上有没有手榴弹
Try him. See if he's got a grenade.
有吗
Anything?
没有
Nah, nothing.
你来看看  能撬开吗
Here, you try having a look. Can you pick it?
希望不能
I hope not.
这锁我花了大价钱的
I paid a lot for that lock.
这里是我的开端  也是你的终点  喜欢吗
How do you like where my journey began and yours ends?
辐射太强我不喜欢
Little radioactive for my taste.
我的命运总是与辐射息息相关
My fate was always bound up with radiation.
我们在没人敢去的地方干活
We'd work where no one else would.
我与恶魔做了交易
I made a bargain with the devil.
用时间换取金钱
Money for time.
出卖自己的未来
We sold our futures.
现在你又要犯下同样的错误
And now you're about to make the same mistake
但这次是毁灭世界
for the entire world.
这不是错误  我自己做了交易
It wasn't a mistake. I made the bargain I could.
你呢
What was yours?
你为不理解的使命而战斗
You fight for a cause you barely understand...
与不信任的人合作
with people you trust so little,
你什么都没告诉他们
you've told them nothing.
我死的时候  整个世界都要陪葬
When I die, the world dies with me.
你知道的事情也随你消逝
And your knowledge dies with you,
就像古埃及的建筑工人一样
buried in a tomb like an anonymous Egyptian builder
带着秘密被埋在金字塔里
sealed in a pyramid to keep his secret.
你的信仰盲目又狂热
Your faith is blind. You're a fanatic.
有什么比试图毁灭世界更狂热呢
What's more fanatical than trying to destroy the world?
并不是  我是想创造新的世界
I'm not, I'm creating a new one.
某时某地
Somewhere, sometime,
一个水晶塔里的人按下了一个开关
a man in a crystalline tower throws a switch
既开启又避免了世界末日
and Armageddon is both triggered and avoided.
现在时间转换了方向
Now time itself switches direction.
我们所沐浴的阳光
The same sunshine we basked in
将温暖我们子孙后代的脸庞
will warm the faces of our descendants generations to come.
他们为什么想杀了我们
How could they wanna kill us?
因为他们的海平面上升  河流干涸
Because their oceans rose and their rivers ran dry.
你还不明白吗  他们别无选择  只能逆转时间
Don't you see? They have no choice but to turn back.
我们是罪魁祸首
We're responsible.
知道这些之后  你还想阻止我吗
Knowing this, do you still want me to stop?
是的
Yes.
每代人都要想方设法生存
Each generation looks out for its own survival.
这正是他们在做的事
That's exactly what they're doing.
但你不是  你是个叛徒
But not you. You're a traitor.
你自己活不久了
Bringing death to all,
就想拉所有人陪葬
because you have no life of your own left.
我事成之后  生命将会延续
When I'm done, life continues.
而你儿子会死
Not your son's.
我最大的罪过就是明知世界将要毁灭
My greatest sin was to bring a son
却还是生下了一个儿子
into a world I knew was ending.
你觉得上帝会宽恕我吗
You think God will forgive me?
等等
Wait!
天啊
God...
掩护我
Cover me!
上  上  上
Go! Go! Go!
你不相信上帝  也不相信未来
You don't believe in God, or a future,
不相信任何超出你经验范围之事
or anything outside of your own experience.
超出的是信仰
The rest is belief.
而我没有信仰
And I don't have it.
没有信仰  你就不是人类
Without it, you're not human.
你只是个疯子
You're just a madman.
或者是神明
Or a god.
差不多吧
Of sorts.
我就说你疯了吧
Like I said.
住手  天啊
Don't. Jesus.
时间到了
Our time is up.
我会替你向我妻子示爱的
I'll give your love to my wife.
你忘了  我这时还没认识她
You're forgetting. I haven't met her yet.
没错
That's right.
你认识她之后  她就死了
After you meet her, she dies.
我还是自己向她示爱吧
I'll just give her my love instead.
不要
Don't do...
沃尔科夫
Volkov...
一枪打爆他的头
别谈生意了  亲爱的
Enough business, my love.
你根本不知道我在说什么吧
You have no idea what I'm talking about, do you?
但听起来是很重要的事
But it sounds terribly important.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
你不热吗
Aren't you hot?
你在做什么
What are you doing now?
我把防晒霜洒出来了
I spilled sunscreen.
-那又怎样  -很滑
- So what? - Slippery!
过来吧
Just come here.
转过去
Turn over.
你会喜欢的
You'll like it.
我装不下去了
I can't do this.
我不能让你以为自己赢了
I can't let you think you've won.
别毁了这一刻的美好  凯特
Don't spoil this moment, Kat.
我不能让你死的时候
I'm not letting you go to your grave
想着我们会为你陪葬
thinking we're coming with you.
你要独自死去  安德烈
You're dying alone, Andrei.
快快快
Come on, come on, come on!
通道和门都封上了
Tunnel's sealed, gate's closed.
马希尔  能收到吗
Mahir, do you copy?
能收到
Yeah.
待命  重复一遍  待命
Hold. I repeat, hold!
看着我的眼睛
Look in my eyes.
你看到了什么
Which do you see?
绝望还是愤怒
Despair or anger?
我不是那个内心被你折磨得伤痕累累
I'm not the woman who could find love for you even though
还能对你心存爱意的女人
you scarred her on the inside.
我是身上被你留下伤疤  心存报复的贱人
I'm the vengeful bitch you scarred on the outside.
不
No!
糟了
Shit.
艾夫斯  她杀了他
Ives, she's killed him.
艾夫斯  收到了吗  她杀了他
Ives, do you copy? She's killed him.
她冲动了  她杀了他
She jumped the gun. She killed him.
快进来  你觉得他们成功了吗
Come on, come on! Do you think they made it?
豁出去了
Screw it.
凯特  你冲动了
Kat! You jumped the gun!
我装不下去了
I couldn't do it.
我不能让他死的时候以为自己赢了
I couldn't let him die thinking he'd won.
我就知道你会有办法的
I knew you'd find a way.
等等  你找到办法了  我们安全了  对吗
Wait, you found a way, we're okay, right?
对  找到办法了  保重
Yeah, found a way. Be safe.
你不是逆时间队的吗
Thought you were inverted.
我中途换回来了
Changed gears halfway.
你们这边似乎需要帮助
Looked like you needed help here.
这边  我们在下面才是真需要帮助
Here? We needed help down there.
你怎么把锁打开的
How'd you get that lock open?
不是我开的  你的小队不需要你吗
Wasn't me. Didn't your team need you?
下次逆转我再跟他们汇合
I'll get 'em on the next pass.
你还好吗  艾夫斯
All right, Ives?
先让我喘口气
Once I've caught my breath.
见过这东西的人不能活着离开
No one who's seen this leaves the field.
好吧
All right.
我们把它藏起来
We hide it.
然后自我了断
We end our lives.
只有这样才能万无一失
That's the only way to be sure.
至于什么时候
As to when...
还是留给大家自己决定吧
maybe that's every man's decision to make for himself.
你不杀我们吗
You're not gonna kill us?
如果让我找到你们  我会的
If I ever find you, I will.
但你不会拼命找吧
But you won't look too hard?
我会的
Yes, I will.
你不会回伦敦看凯特吧
You're not going back to London to check on Kat, are you?
不会  太危险了
No. It's far too dangerous.
远远看一眼也不会吗
Even from afar?
远远看一眼也不会
Even from afar.
艾夫斯
Ives!
等等
Wait.
你真的要逆转回去吗
Are you really going back in?
只有我才能
I'm the only one who could've
及时打开那扇门  对吧  艾夫斯
got that door open in time, right, Ives?
你是我见过开锁技术最好的
Well, I don't know any locksmiths as good as you.
懂了吧
See?
里面那个人又是我
It's me in there, again.
为这个任务的又一重过去穿针引线
Weaving another past in the fabric of this mission.
尼尔  等等
Neil, wait!
刚拯救完世界
Just saved the world.
不能留下任何隐患
Can't leave anything to chance.
但是做不一样的选择  能改变发生的事吗
But can we change things if we do it differently?
"发生过的事已经发生了"
"What's happened's happened."
这是对于世界运转的信念
Which is an expression of faith in the mechanics of the world.
而非袖手旁观的借口
It's not an excuse to do nothing.
是命运吗
Fate?
你觉得是什么就是什么
Call it what you want.
你觉得是什么
What do you call it?
现实
Reality.
让我走吧
Now let me go.
你还没告诉我是谁招募了你  尼尔
You never did tell me who recruited you, Neil.
你还没猜出来吗
Haven't you guessed by now?
是你啊
You did.
但不是你想的时间
Only not when you thought.
你在过去有一段未来
You have a future in the past.
我的过去  你的未来
Years ago for me. Years from now for you.
你认识我很多年了吗
You've known me for years?
对我来说  这是一段美好友谊的结束
For me, I think this is the end of a beautiful friendship.
但对我来说  这只是开始
But for me, it's just the beginning.
我们有不少经历
We get up to some stuff.
你一定喜欢  等着瞧吧
You're gonna love it. You'll see.
整个任务就是一次时间钳形行动
This whole operation's a temporal pincer.
谁的任务
Whose?
你的
Yours!
你才走了一半
You're only halfway there.
在起点见吧  朋友
I'll see you at the beginning, friend.
我们是拯救可能毁灭的世界的人
We're the people saving the world from what might have been.
世人永远不会知道本来可能发生什么
World will never know what could've happened.
即使他们知道了  也不会在乎
And even if they did, they wouldn't care.
因为不会有人在乎没有引爆的炸弹
'Cause no one cares about the bomb that didn't go off.
西北三区加农街
他们只在乎引爆了的炸弹
Only the one that did.
在孩子出来前动手
Do it before the boy comes out.
这就是你的仁慈吗
That's your idea of mercy?
你向我保证过
You gave me your word.
我当时就说了  保证没什么意义
And I told you then what it would be worth.
此时  此地
Here, today.
你是怎么知道的
How did you know?
加农街  3点  大概没什么  我...
Cannon Place, 3:00. Probably nothing, I'm...
未来的人
Posterity.
加农街  3点  大概没什么  我...
Cannon Place, 3:00. Probably nothing, I'm...
我跟你说过该换个方式看待世界了
I told you you'd have to start looking differently at the world.
我必须解决后患
I have to tie up the loose ends.
这从来就不是你的任务
That was never your job.
那是谁的
Then whose was it?
我的
Mine.
我意识到我不是你的手下
I realized I wasn't working for you.
你我都是我的手下
We've both been working for me.
我是主角
I'm the protagonist.
那你最好赶快解决后患
Then you'd better tie up those loose ends.
任务完成
Mission accomplished.
没有引爆的炸弹
It's the bomb that didn't go off.
没人察觉的威胁
The danger no one knew was real.
西北三区加农街
那才是足以改变世界的力量
That's the bomb with the real power to change the world.